Okay. Hello everyone.
好的。大家好。
[LAUGHTER] Okay we should get started.
[大笑]好的，我们应该开始吧。
Um, they're actually are still quite a few seats left.
嗯，他们实际上还剩下不少座位。
If you wanna be really bold,
如果你想真的很大胆，
there are a couple of seats right in front of me in the front row.
前排有几个座位就在我面前。
If you're less bolder a few over there.
如果你在那里不那么大胆。
Um, but they're also on some of the rows are quite a few middle seat.
嗯，但他们也在一些行上有相当多的中间座位。
So if people wanted to be really civic minded some people could sort of
因此，如果人们想成为一个真正的公民意识，有些人可能会有所不同
squeeze towards the edges and make  more accessible um,
挤向边缘，使更容易接近，
some of the seats that still exist in the classroom.
教室里仍然存在一些席位。
Okay. Um, so, um,
好的。嗯，恩，嗯，
it's really exciting and great to see so many people here.
看到这么多人真是令人兴奋和高兴。
So I'm a hearty welcome to CS224N and occasionally also
所以我对CS224N表示热烈欢迎，偶尔也欢迎
known as Ling 284 which is Natural Language Processing with Deep Learning.
被称为Ling 284，它是深度学习的自然语言处理。
Um, as just a sort of a  personal anecdote,
嗯，只是一种个人轶事，
is still sort of blows my mind that so many people turn up to this class these days.
我觉得这些日子里有这么多人上这堂课了。
So, for about the first decade that I taught NLP here,
那么，我在这里教授NLP的第一个十年，
you know the number of people I got each year was approximately 45.
你知道我每年得到的人数约为45人。
[LAUGHTER] So it's an order of [LAUGHTER] magnitude smaller than
[大笑]所以这是[笑声]大小的顺序
it is now but guess it says quite a lot
它现在但是猜它说了很多
on about what a revolutionary   impact
关于什么是革命性的影响
that artificial intelligence in general and machine learning,
人工智能一般和机器学习，
deep learning, NLP are starting to have in modern society.
深度学习，NLP开始在现代社会中发挥作用。
Okay. So this is our plan for today.
好的。所以这是我们今天的计划。
So, um, um, we're really gonna get straight down to business today.
所以，嗯，嗯，我们今天真的要开始做生意了。
So they'll be a brief, very brief introduction some of the sort of course logistics,
因此，他们将简要介绍一些课程后勤，
very brief discussion and talk about human language and
非常简短的讨论和谈论人类语言和
word meaning and then we wanna get right into talking about um,
单词含义，然后我们想谈谈你，
the first thing that we're doing which is coming up with word vectors and looking
我们正在做的第一件事是提出单词向量和看
at the word2vec algorithm and that will then sort of fill up the rest of the class.
在word2vec算法，然后将填写其余的类。
There are still two seats right in
还有两个席位
the front row for someone who wants to sit right in front of me,
想要坐在我面前的人的前排，
just letting you know [LAUGHTER].
只是让你知道[笑声]。
Okay. Okay. So here are the course logistics in brief.
好的。好的。所以这里是课程后勤简介。
So I'm Christopher Manning,
所以我是克里斯托弗曼宁，
the person who bravely became the head TA is Abigail See is right there.
勇敢地成为TA主管的人是Abigail See就在那里。
And then we have quite a lot of wonderful TA's.
然后我们有很多很棒的TA。
To the people who are wonderful TA's just sort of stand up for one moment.
对于那些精彩TA的人来说，只是站了一会儿。
So, um, [LAUGHTER] we have some sense for wonderful TAs.
所以，嗯，[笑声]我们对美妙的TA有一定的感觉。
[LAUGHTER] Okay great.
[大笑]好的。
Um, okay.
嗯，好的。
So you know when the lecture is because you made it
所以你知道讲座的时间是因为你做到了
here and so welcome also to SCPD people.
在这里，也欢迎SCPD人。
This is also an SCPD class and you can watch it on video.
这也是一个SCPD课程，您可以在视频中观看。
But we love for Stanford students to turn
但我们喜欢斯坦福大学的学生
up and show their beautiful faces in the classroom.
在教室里展示他们美丽的面孔。
Okay. So, um, the web-page has all the info about syllabus et cetera et cetera.
好的。所以，嗯，网页上有关于教学大纲等等的所有信息。
Okay. So this class what do we hope to teach?
好的。那么这堂课我们希望教什么？
So, one thing that we wanna teach is, uh, you know,
所以，我们想教的一件事是，呃，你知道，
an understanding of effective modern methods for deep learning.
了解有效的现代深度学习方法。
Starting off by reviewing some of the basics and then
首先回顾一些基础知识然后
particularly talking about the kinds of techniques including um,
特别是谈论包括嗯在内的各种技术，
recurrent networks and attention that are widely
反复出现的网络和广泛的关注
used for natural language processing models.
用于自然语言处理模型。
A second thing we wanna teach is a big picture understanding of
我们想要教的第二件事是对大局的全面了解
human languages and some of the difficulties in understanding and producing them.
人类语言以及理解和产生它们的一些困难。
Of course if you wanna know a lot about human languages,
当然，如果你想了解很多关于人类语言的知识，
there's a whole linguistics department and you can do a lot of courses of that.
这里有一个完整的语言学系，你可以做很多课程。
Um, but so I wanna give at least some appreciation so you have some clue of what are
嗯，但是我想至少给予一些赞赏，所以你有一些线索是什么
the challenges and difficulties and varieties of human languages.
人类语言的挑战，困难和多样性。
And then this is also kind of a practical class.
然后这也是一个实用的课程。
Like we actually wanna teach you how you can
就像我们真的想教你怎么做
build practical systems that work for some of the major parts of NLP.
构建适用于NLP某些主要部分的实用系统。
So if you go and get a job at one of those tech firms and they say "Hey,
所以，如果你去其中一家科技公司找工作，他们说“嘿，
could you build us a named entity recognizer?"
你能为我们建立一个命名的实体识别器吗？“
You can say "Sure, I can do that."
你可以说“当然，我能做到。”
And so for a bunch of problems,
对于一堆问题，
obviously we can't do everything,
显然我们无法做到一切，
we're gonna do word meaning,
我们会做单词的意思，
dependency parsing, machine translation and you have an option to do question answering,
依赖解析，机器翻译，你可以选择进行问答，
I'm actually building systems for those.
我实际上正在为那些人构建系统。
If you'd been talking to friends who did the class in the last couple of years,
如果你和过去几年上课的朋友说话，
um, here are the differences for this year just to get things straight.
嗯，今年的差异只是为了让事情顺利进行。
Um, so we've updated some of the content of the course.
嗯，所以我们更新了课程的一些内容。
So, uh, between me and guest lectures there's new content.
所以，呃，在我和客座讲座之间有新的内容。
Well that look bad.
那看起来很糟糕。
Wonder if that will keep happening, we'll find out.
不管怎么说会继续发生，我们会发现。
There's new content and on various topics that are sort of developing areas.
有新的内容和各种主题，这些都是发展中的领域。
One of the problems with this course is really big area of deep learning at
这门课程的一个问题是深度学习的重要领域
the moment is still just developing really really quickly.
现在仍然只是真正快速发展。
So, it's sort of seems like one-year-old content is already
所以，它似乎已经有一年的内容了
things kind of data and we're trying to update things.
事情类型的数据，我们正在尝试更新的东西。
A big change that we're making this year is we're
我们今年要做的一个重大变化就是我们
having five-one week assignments instead of
有五个星期的任务而不是
three-two week assignments at the beginning of
在开始的三个两周的任务
the course and I'll say a bit more about that in a minute.
这个课程，我会在一分钟内再说一点。
Um, this year we're gonna use PyTorch instead of TensorFlow,
嗯，今年我们要用PyTorch而不是TensorFlow，
and we'll talk about that more later too.
我们稍后会再讨论这个问题。
Um, we're having the assignments due before class on either Tuesday or Thursday.
嗯，我们要在课前的周二或周四完成作业。
So you're not distracted and can come to class.
所以你不会分心，可以上课。
So starting off, um, yeah.
所以开始，嗯，是的。
So we're trying to give an easier,
所以我们试图让一个更容易，
gentler ramp-up but on the other hand a fast ramp-up.
温和的提升，但另一方面快速提升。
So we've got this first assignment which is sort of easy, uh,
所以我们有了第一个任务，这很简单，呃，
but it's available right now and is due next Tuesday.
但它现在可用，将于下周二到期。
And the final thing is we're not having a midterm this year.
最后一件事是我们今年没有中期。
Um, okay.
嗯，好的。
So this is what we're doing.
所以这就是我们正在做的事情。
So there are five of these assignments that I just mentioned.
所以我刚才提到的这些任务中有五项。
Um, So six percent for the first one,
嗯，第一个百分之六，
12 percent for each of the other ones,
每个其他的12％，
um, and, I already said that.
嗯，我已经说过了。
We're gonna use gradescope for grading.
我们将使用成绩镜进行评分。
It'll be really help out the TAs if you could use
如果可以的话，它将真正帮助你
your SUnet ID as your gradescope account ID.
您的SUnet ID是您的gradecope帐户ID。
Um, so then for the second part of the course,
嗯，那么对于课程的第二部分，
people do a final project and there are two choices for the final project.
人们做最后的项目，最终项目有两种选择。
You can either do our default final project,
你可以做我们默认的最终项目，
which is a good option for many people,
对很多人来说这是个不错的选择，
or you can do a custom final project and I'll
或者你可以做一个自定义的最终项目，我会
talk about that in the more in the beginning.
在一开始就谈论这个。
This is not working right.
这不行。
Um, and so then at the end we have
嗯，所以最后我们有
a final poster presentation session at which your attendance is expected,
最后的海报展示会，期待您的出席，
and we're gonna be having that Wednesday in the evening.
我们将在周三晚上举行。
Probably not quite five hours but it'll be within that window,
可能不会超过五个小时，但它会在那个窗口内，
we'll work out the details in a bit.
我们稍后会弄清楚细节。
Three percent for participation,
百分之三的参与，
see the website for details.
有关详细信息，请访问网站
Six late days, um,
六天晚些时候，嗯，
collaboration, like always in computer science classes,
合作，就像计算机科学课一样，
we want you to do your own work and not borrow stuff from other people's Githubs and
我们希望你做自己的工作，而不是借用其他人的Githubs和
so we really do emphasize that you should
所以我们确实强调你应该这样做
read and pay attention to collaboration policies.
阅读并注意协作政策。
Okay. So here's the high level plan for the problem sets.
好的。所以这是问题集的高级计划。
So, homework one available right now,
所以，现在可以做作业，
is a hopefully easy on ramp.
是一个希望轻松的坡道。
That's on iPython notebook,
这是在iPython笔记本上，
just help get everyone up to speed.
只是帮助每个人加快速度。
Homework two is pure Python plus numpy but that
作业二是纯粹的Python加上numpy但是那个
will start to kind of teach you more about the sort of underlying,
会开始教你更多关于底层的东西，
how do we do deep learning.
我们如何做深度学习。
If you're not so good or a bit rusty or never seen um,
如果你不是那么好或有点生疏或从未见过嗯，
Python or numpy, um,
Python或numpy，嗯，
we're gonna have an extra section on Friday.
我们星期五会有一个额外的部分。
So Friday from 1:30 to 2:50 um,
星期五从1:30到2:50，
in Skilling Auditorium, we'll have a section that's a Python review.
在Skilling Auditorium中，我们将有一个Python评论部分。
That's our only plan section at the moment,
那是我们目前唯一的计划部分，
we're not gonna have a regular section.
我们不会有常规部分。
Um, so encourage to go to that and that will also be
嗯，所以鼓励去那，那也是
recorded for SCPD and available for video as well.
为SCPD录制并可用于视频。
Um, then Homework three um,
嗯，然后家庭作业三嗯，
will start us on using PyTorch.
我们将开始使用PyTorch。
And then homeworks four and five we're then gonna be using
然后我们将使用四个和五个家庭作业
py- PyTorch on GPU and we're actually gonna be using
在GPU上py-PyTorch，我们实际上将要使用
Microsoft Azure with big thank yous to the kind Microsoft Azure people who have
Microsoft Azure非常感谢那些拥有Microsoft Azure的人
sponsored our GPU computing for the last um, three years.
赞助我们的GPU计算最后一年，三年。
Um, yes. So basically I mean all of modern deep learning has moved to the use
嗯，是的。所以基本上我的意思是所有现代深度学习都转向了使用
of one or other of the large deep learning libraries like PyTorch TensorFlow,
一个或多个大型深度学习库，如PyTorch TensorFlow，
Chainer or MXNet um,
Chainer或MXNet嗯，
et cetera and then doing the computing on GPU.
等等，然后在GPU上进行计算。
So of course since we're in the one building,
所以当然，因为我们在一栋楼里
we should of course be using, um,
我们当然应该使用，嗯，
GPUs [LAUGHTER] but I mean in general
GPU [笑声]但我的意思是一般的
the so parallelisms scalability of GPUs is what's powered most of modern deep learning.
GPU的并行性可扩展性是大多数现代深度学习的动力。
Okay. The final project.
好的。最后的项目。
So for the final project there are two things that you can do.
因此，对于最终项目，您可以做两件事。
So we have a default final project which is essentially our final project in a box.
所以我们有一个默认的最终项目，它本质上是我们在一个盒子里的最终项目。
And so this is building a question answering system and we do it over the squad dataset.
所以这是建立一个问答系统，我们在小队数据集上做。
So what you build and how you can improve your performance is completely up to you.
因此，您构建的内容以及如何提高性能完全取决于您。
It is open-ended but it has an easier start,
它是开放式的，但它有一个更容易的开始，
a clearly defined objective and we can
一个明确定义的目标，我们可以
have a leaderboard for how well things are working.
有一个排行榜，了解事情的运作情况。
Um, so if you don't have a clear research objective that can be a good choice for you
嗯，如果你没有一个明确的研究目标，那对你来说是个不错的选择
or you can propose the custom Final Project and  assuming it's sensible,
或者您可以提出自定义最终项目并假设它是明智的，
we will approve your custom final project,
我们将批准您的自定义最终项目，
we will give you feedback, um,
我们会给你反馈，嗯，
form someone as a mentor, um,
把某人当作导师，嗯，
and either way for only the final project we allow teams of one, two or three.
无论哪种方式，只有最终项目我们允许一，二或三队。
For the homework should expect it to do them yourself.
对于家庭作业应该期望它自己做。
Of course you can chat to people in a general way about the problems.
当然，您可以通过一般方式与人们聊聊问题。
Okay. So that is the course.
好的。这就是课程。
All good, and not even behind schedule yet.
一切都很好，甚至还没有落后于时间表。
Okay. So the next section is human language and word meaning.Um.
好的。所以接下来的部分是人类语言和词义。嗯。
You know, if I was um,
你知道，如果我是，
really going to tell you a lot about human language that would take a lot of time um,
真的会告诉你很多关于人类语言会花很多时间的事情，
which I don't really have here.
我真的不在这里。
So I'm just going to tell you um,
所以我只想告诉你，嗯，
two anecdotes about human language.
关于人类语言的两个轶事。
And the first is this XKCD cartoon.
首先是这张XKCD卡通片。
Um, and I mean this isn't,
嗯，我的意思是这不是，
and I don't know why that's happening.
我不知道为什么会这样。
I'm not sure what to make of that.
我不知道该怎么做。
Um, so, I actually really liked this XKCD cartoon.
嗯，所以，我其实非常喜欢这款XKCD卡通片。
It's not one of the classic ones that you see most often around the place,
它不是你经常在这个地方看到的经典之作，
but I actually think it says a lot about language and is worth thinking about.
但我实际上认为它说的很多语言，值得思考。
Like I think a lot of the time for the kind of people who come
就像我认为很多人来的那种时候
to this class who are mainly people like CS people,
这个班主要是CS人，
and EE people and random others.
和EE人和随机的其他人。
There's some other people I know since these people linguists and so on around.
自从这些人语言学家等以来，我知道其他一些人。
But for a lot of those people like,
但对于很多人来说，
you've sort of spent your life looking at formal languages and the impression
你有点花在生活中看正式的语言和印象
is that sort of human language as a sort of somehow a little bit broken formal languages,
是那种人类语言，有点像一些破坏的形式语言，
but there's really a lot more to it than that, right?
但它真的还有很多，对吗？
That language is this amazing um,
那语言真是太神奇了，
human created system that is used for
人类创建的系统用于
all sorts of purposes and is adaptable to all sorts of purposes.
各种各样的目的，适应各种目的。
So you can do everything from describing mathematics and human language
所以你可以通过描述数学和人类语言来做所有事情
um to sort of nuzzling up to your best friend and getting them to understand you better.
嗯，为了你最好的朋友，让他们更好地了解你。
So there's actually an amazing thing of human language. Anyway, I'll just read it.
所以人类语言实际上是一件令人惊奇的事情。无论如何，我只是读它。
Um, so it's the first person,
嗯，所以这是第一个人，
the dark haired person says,
黑头发的人说，
"Anyway, I could care less."
“无论如何，我可以少关心。”
And her friend says,
而她的朋友说，
"I think you mean you couldn't care less."
“我想你的意思是你不在乎。”
Saying you could care less implies you care at least some amount.
说你可以少关心意味着你至少关心一些金额。
And the dark haired person says, "I don't know,
黑头发的人说：“我不知道，
we're these unbelievably complicated brains drifting through a void trying
我们是这些令人难以置信的复杂大脑在虚空中徘徊
in vain to connect with one another by blindly flinging words out into the darkness."
盲目地将文字扔进黑暗中，相互联系是徒劳的。“
Every choice of phrasing and spelling, and tone,
每个选择的措辞和拼写，以及语气，
and timing carries countless signals and contexts and subtexts and more.
和时间带有无数的信号和上下文和子文字等等。
And every listener interprets those signals in their own way.
每个听众都以自己的方式解释这些信号。
Language isn't a formal system,
语言不是正式的系统，
language is glorious chaos.
语言是光荣的混乱。
You can never know for sure what any words will mean to anyone.
你永远无法确定任何单词对任何人都意味着什么。
All you can do is try to get better at guessing how your words affect people so
你所能做的就是尽量好好猜测你的话语如何影响人们
you can have a chance of finding the ones that will make
你有机会找到那些会做的
them feel something like what you want them to feel.
他们感受到了你想让他们感受到的东西。
Everything else is pointless.
其他一切都毫无意义。
I assume you're giving me tips on how you interpret
我假设你给我提示你如何解释
words because you want me to feel less alone.
因为你希望我感觉不那么孤单。
If so, thank you.
如果是的话，谢谢。
That means a lot.
这意味着很多。
But if you're just running my sentences past
但是，如果你只是把我的句子过去了
some mental checklist so you can show off how well you know it,
一些心理检查表，以便你可以炫耀你对它的了解程度，
then I could care less.
然后我可以少关心。
[NOISE] Um, and so I think um,
[NOISE]嗯，所以我想，嗯，
I think actually this has some nice messages about how language is this uncertain
我认为实际上这有一些关于语言如何不确定的好消息
evolved system of communication but somehow we have enough agreed meaning that you know,
进化的通信系统，但不知何故，我们有足够的同意，你知道，
we can kind of pretty much communicate.
我们几乎可以沟通。
But we're doing some kind of you know
但我们正在做某种你知道的事情
probabilistic inference of guessing what people mean and we're
猜测人们的意思和我们的概率推理
using language not just for
使用语言不仅仅是为了
the information functions but for the social functions etc etc.
信息功能，但社会功能等。
Okay. And then here's my one other thought I had review about language.
好的。然后这是我的另一个想法，我已经审查了语言。
So, essentially if we want to have artificial intelligence that's intelligent,
所以，基本上如果我们想拥有智能的人工智能，
what we need to somehow get to the point of having
我们需要以某种方式达到目的
compu- computers that have the knowledge of human beings, right?
拥有人类知识的计算机，对吧？
Because human beings have knowledge that gives them intelligence.
因为人类拥有能够为他们提供智慧的知识。
And if you think about how we sort of
如果你考虑我们如何排序
convey knowledge around the place in our human world,
传达我们人类世界中的知识，
mainly the way we do it is through human language.
主要是我们这样做的方式是通过人类语言。
You know, some kinds of knowledge you can sort of
你知道，你可以使用某些类型的知识
work out for yourself by doing physical stuff right,
通过做正确的事情来为自己锻炼，
I can hold this and drop that and I've learnt something.
我能抓住这一点并放弃它，我已经学到了一些东西。
So I have to learn a bit of knowledge there.
所以我必须在那里学到一些知识。
But sort of most of the knowledge in your heads and why you're sitting in
但是你头脑中的大部分知识和你为什么坐在那里
this classroom has come from people communicating in human language to you.
这个教室来自人们用人类语言沟通的人。
Um, so one of the famous,
嗯，所以其中一个着名的，
most famous steep learning people Yann Le Cun,
最着名的陡峭学习者Yann Le Cun，
he likes to say this line about,
他喜欢说这句话，
oh, you know really I think that you know there's not much difference
哦，你知道我认为你知道没有太大区别
between the intelligence of human being and orangutan.
在人类的智慧和猩猩之间。
And I actually think he's really wrong on that.
而我实际上认为他真的错了。
Like the sense in which he means that is,
就像他所说的意义一样，
an orangutan has a really good vision system.
猩猩有一个非常好的视觉系统。
Orangutans have very good you know control of
你知道猩猩非常善于控制
their arms just like human beings for picking things up.
他们的手臂就像人类一样捡东西。
Orangutans um can use tools um and orangutans can make plans so
猩猩可以使用工具，猩猩可以制定计划
that if you sort of put the food somewhere where they have to sort of move
如果你把食物放在他们必须移动的地方
the plank to get to the island with the food they can do a plan like that.
用食物来到岛上的木板，他们可以做这样的计划。
So yeah, in a sense they've got a fair bit of intelligence but you know,
所以是的，从某种意义上说，他们有一点智慧，但你知道，
sort of orangutans just aren't like human beings.
有点猩猩不像人类。
And why aren't they like human beings?
他们为什么不喜欢人类？
And I'd like to suggest to you the reason for that is what human beings have achieved is,
我想告诉你，人类取得的成就是什么，
we don't just have sort of one computer like
我们不仅仅有一台计算机
a you know dusty old IBM PC in your mother's garage.
你知道母亲车库里装满尘土的旧PC。
What we have is a human computer network.
我们拥有的是人机界面。
And the way that we've achieved that human computer network is that,
我们实现人机计算机网络的方式是，
we use human languages as our networking language.
我们使用人类语言作为我们的网络语言。
Um, and so, when you think about it um,
嗯，当你想到它时，嗯，
so on any kind of evolutionary scale language is super super super super recent, right?
那么任何一种进化规模的语言都是超级超级超级近期，对吧？
That um, creatures have had vision for people don't quite know but you know,
那个嗯，生物对人有远见但不知道，但你知道，
maybe it's 75 million years or maybe it's longer, right?
也许它是7500万年或者可能更长，对吧？
A huge length of time.
很长的时间。
How long have human beings have had language?
人类有多长时间有语言？
You know people don't know that either because it turns out you know,
你知道人们也不知道，因为结果你知道，
when you have fossils,
当你有化石时，
you can't knock the skull on the side and say,
你不能把头骨撞到一边然后说，
do you not have language.
你没有语言吗？
Um, but you know, most people estimate that sort of language is
嗯，但是你知道，大多数人估计那种语言是
a very recent invention before current human beings moved out of um, out of Africa.
在现在的人类离开非洲之前，这是一项非常新的发明。
So that many people think that we've only had language for
因此，许多人认为我们只有语言
something like a 100,000 years or something like that.
像10万年或类似的事情。
So that's sort of you know blink of an eye on the evolutionary timescale.
因此，您可以在进化时间尺度上眨眼。
But you know, it was the development of language [inaudible]
但是你知道，这是语言的发展[音频不清晰]
that sort of made human beings invisible- [NOISE] in invincible, right?
这种让人类看不见 -  [NOISE]立于不败之地，对吧？
It wasn't that, human beings um,
不是这样，人类嗯，
developed poison fangs or developed ability to run
发展出毒牙或发达的能力
faster than any other creature or
比任何其他生物或更快
put a big horn on their heads or something like that, right?
在他们的头上放一个大喇叭或类似的东西，对吧？
You know, humans are basically pretty puny um,
你知道，人类基本上都很乖，
but they had this um,
但他们有这个，
unbeatable advantage that they could communicate with
他们可以与之沟通的无与伦比的优势
each other and therefore work much more effectively in teams.
彼此，因此在团队中更有效地工作。
And that sort of basically made human beings invincible.
而这种基本上使人类立于不败之地。
But you know, even then humans were kind of limited, right?
但是你知道，即使那时人类也有限，对吧？
That kind of got you to about the Stone Age right,
那种让你了解石器时代的权利，
where you could bang on your stones and with
在那里你可以敲打你的石头和
the right kind of stone make something sharp to cut with.
正确的石头使切割的东西变得锋利。
Um, what got humans beyond that,
嗯，是什么让人类超越了这个，
was that they invented writing.
是他们发明了写作。
So writing was then an ability where you could take knowledge
因此，写作是一种你可以学习知识的能力
not only communicated um mouth to mouth to people that you saw.
不仅与你见过的人口口相传。
You could put it down on your piece of papyrus so your clay tablet or whatever
你可以把它放在你的纸莎草上，这样你的粘土片或其他什么
it was at first and that knowledge could then be sent places.
起初它是知识，然后可以发送知识。
It could be sent spatially around the world and it could then
它可以在世界范围内空间发送，然后可以
be sent temporally through time.
通过时间暂时发送。
And well, how old is writing?
好吧，写作多大了？
I mean, we sort of basically know about how old writing is, right?
我的意思是，我们基本上都知道写作有多久，对吧？
That writing is about 5,000 years old.
那篇文章大约有5000年的历史。
It's incredibly incredibly recent on this scale of evolution but you know,
在这种进化规模上，这是令人难以置信的最近，但你知道，
essentially writing was so powerful as a way of having knowledge that then in those 5,000
基本上写作是如此强大，以至于拥有知识的方式，然后在那5000个
years that enabled human beings to go from stone age sharp piece or flint to you know,
多年让人类从石器时代的尖锐片段或燧石中走出来，你知道，
having iPhones and all of these things,
拥有iPhone和所有这些东西，
all these incredibly sophisticated devices.
所有这些非常复杂的设备。
So, language is pretty special thing I'd like to suggest.
因此，语言是我想提出的非常特别的事情。
Um, but you know, if I go back to my analogy that sort of it's allowed humans to
嗯，但是你知道，如果我回到我的类比，那是允许人类做的那种
construct a networked computer that is way way more powerful than um,
构建一个比um更强大的联网计算机，
just having individual creatures as sort of intelligent like an orangutan.
只是让个体生物像猩猩一样聪明。
Um, and you compare it to our computer networks,
嗯，你把它与我们的计算机网络进行比较，
it's a really funny kind of network, right?
这是一个非常有趣的网络，对吧？
You know that these days um,
你知道这些天嗯，
we have networks that run around where we have sort of large network bandwidth, right?
我们有网络，我们有大量的网络带宽，对吧？
You know, we might be frustrated sometimes with
你知道，我们有时可能会感到沮丧
our Netflix downloads but by and large you know,
我们的Netflix下载但总的来说，你知道，
we can download hundreds of megabytes really easily and quickly.
我们可以非常轻松快速地下载数百兆字节。
And we don't think that's fast enough,
我们认为这不够快，
so we're going to be rolling out 5G networks.
所以我们将推出5G网络。
So it's an order of magnitude faster again.
所以它再次快一个数量级。
I mean, by comparison to that, I mean,
我的意思是，相比之下，我的意思是，
human language is a pathetically slow network, right?
人类语言是一个可怜的慢网络吧？
That the amount of information you can convey by human language is very slow.
您可以通过人类语言传达的信息量非常慢。
I mean you know, whatever it is I sort of speak at about 15 words a second right,
我的意思是你知道，无论是什么，我都会说出大约15个单词的权利，
you can start doing um,
你可以开始做嗯，
your information theory if you know some right?
你的信息理论，如果你知道一些吗？
But um, you don't actually get much bandwidth at all.
但是，嗯，实际上你根本没有获得多少带宽。
And that then leads- so you can think of,
然后导致 - 所以你可以想到，
how does it work then?
它是如何工作的呢？
So, humans have come up with
所以，人类已经想到了
this incredibly impressive system which is essentially form of compression.
这个令人难以置信的令人印象深刻的系
Sort of a very adaptive form of compression,
一种非常自适应的压缩形式，
so that when we're talking to people,
这样当我们与人交谈时，
we assume that they have an enormous amount of knowledge in their heads which
我们假设他们头脑中有大量的知识
isn't the same as but it's broadly similar to mine when I'm talking to you right?
当我和你说话的时候，它与我的大致相似？
That you know what English words mean,
你知道英文单词的意思，
and you know a lot about how the wor- world works.
而且你对这个世界的运作方式了解很多。
And therefore, I can say a short message and communicate
因此，我可以说一条短信并进行沟通
only a relatively short bit string and you can actually understand a lot. All right?
只有一个相对较短的位串，你实际上可以理解很多。行？
So, I can say sort of whatever you know,
所以，我可以说你所知道的一切，
imagine a busy shopping mall and that
想象一下繁忙的购物中心
there are two guys standing in front of a makeup counter,
有两个人站在化妆柜台前，
and you know I've only said whatever that was sort of about 200 bits of
而且你知道我只说了大约200比特的东西
information but that's enabled you to construct
信息，但这使你能够构建
a whole visual scene that we're taking megabytes to um,
一个完整的视觉场景，我们花费了几兆字节，
represent as an image.
表示为图像。
So, that's why language is good.
所以，这就是语言好的原因。
Um, so from that more authorial level,
嗯，从更多的作者级别来看，
I'll now move back to the concrete stuff.
我现在回到具体的东西。
What we wanna do in this class is not solve the whole of language,
我们想在这堂课中做的不是解决整个语言，
but we want to represent, um,
但我们要代表，嗯，
the meaning of words, right?
话语的意思吧？
So, a lot of language is bound up in words and their meanings
所以，很多语言都与单词及其含义有关
and words can have really rich meanings, right?
言语可以有丰富的意义，对吧？
As soon as you say a word teacher,
一说一句老师，
that's kinda quite a lot of rich meaning or you can have actions that have rich meaning.
这有很多丰富的意义，或者你可以采取具有丰富意义的行动。
So, if I say a word like prognosticate or,
所以，如果我说一个像预测的话，或者，
um, total or something you know,
嗯，总或你知道的，
these words that have rich meanings and a lot of nuance on them.
这些词语含义丰富，细微之处。
And so we wanna represent meaning.
所以我们想要代表意义。
And so, the question is what is meaning?
所以，问题是什么意思？
So, you can of course you can- dictionaries are meant to tell you about meanings.
所以，你当然可以告诉你有关词义的意思。
So, you can look up dictionaries um,
所以，你可以查找词典，嗯，
and Webster says sort of tries to relate meaning to idea.
而韦伯斯特则试图将意义与想法联系起来。
The idea that is represented by a word or a phrase.
由单词或短语表示的想法。
The idea that a person wants to express by word signs et cetera.
一个人想通过文字符号等表达的想法。
I mean, you know,
我的意思是，你知道，
you could think that these definitions are kind of a cop-out because it seems
你可以认为这些定义似乎是一种警察，因为它似乎
like they're rewriting meaning in terms of the word idea,
就像他们用词的想法重写意义一样，
and is that really gotten you anywhere.
这真的让你在任何地方。
Um, how do linguists think about meaning?
嗯，语言学家如何看待意义？
I mean, the most common way that linguists have thought about
我的意思是，语言学家最常见的思考方式
meaning is an idea that's called denotational
意思是一种被称为指称的想法
semantics which is also used in programming languages.
语义，也用于编程语言。
So, the idea of that is we think of meaning as what things represent.
所以，我们的想法是将意义视为事物的代表。
So, if I say the word chair,
所以，如果我说“椅子”这个词，
the denotation of the word chair includes this one here and that one,
主题一词的含​​义包括这一个和那一个，
that one, that one, that one.
那个，那一个，那个。
And so, the word chair is sort of representing
因此，椅子这个词有点代表
all the things that are chairs and you can sort of, um,
所有椅子都可以，你可以这样，嗯，
you can then think of something like running as well that you know there's sort of sets
然后，你可以想到像跑步一样的东西，你知道那里有一套
of actions that people can partake that- that's their denotation.
人们可以参与的行动 - 这是他们的外延。
And that's sort of what you most commonly see in philosophy or linguistics as denotation.
这就是你在哲学或语言学中最常见的那些作为外延的东西。
It's kind of a hard thing to get your hands on, um, computationally.
这是一件很难接触的事，嗯，计算上。
So, um, what type of people most commonly
所以，嗯，最常见的是什么类型的人
do or use the most commonly do I guess I should say now
做或最常用的我想我现在应该说
for working out the meaning of words on the computer that
用于解决计算机上的文字含义
commonly that turn to something that was a bit like a dictionary.
通常转向有点像字典的东西。
In particular favorite online thing was this online thesaurus called WordNet which
特别喜欢在线的东西是这个名为WordNet的在线词库
sort of tells you about word meanings and relationships between word meanings.
有点告诉你关于词义和词义之间的关系。
Um, so this is just giving you the very slices sense of,
嗯，所以这只是给你切片的感觉，
um, of what's in WordNet.
嗯，WordNet中的内容。
Um, so this is an actual bit of Python code up there which you can,
嗯，所以这是一个Python代码的实际位，你可以，
um, type into your computer and run and do this for yourself.
嗯，输入您的计算机并运行并为自己执行此操作。
Um, so this uses a thing called NLTK.
嗯，所以这使用了一个名为NLTK的东西。
Um, so NLTK is sort of like
嗯，所以NLTK有点像
the "Swiss Army Knife of NLP" meaning that it's not terribly good for anything,
“NLP的瑞士军刀”意味着它对任何东西都不是非常好，
but it has a lot of basic tools.
但它有很多基本工具。
So, if you wanted to do something like just get some stuff out of WordNet and show it,
所以，如果你想做一些事情，比如从WordNet中获取一些东西并展示它，
it's the perfect thing to use. Um, okay.
这是完美的选择。嗯，好的。
So, um, from NLTK I'm importing WordNet and so then I can say,
所以，嗯，来自NLTK，我正在导入WordNet，所以我可以说，
"Okay, um, for the word good tell me about the synonym sets with good participates in."
“好吧，嗯，好的这个词告诉我关于同义词集的好参与。”
And there's good goodness as a noun.
并且作为名词有很好的善良。
There is an adjective good.
形容词很好。
There's one estimable good, honorable, respectable.
有一个可敬的好，尊贵，可敬。
Um, this looks really complex and hard to understand.
嗯，这看起来很复杂，很难理解。
But the idea of word- WordNet makes
但是WordNet的想法使得
these very fine grain distinctions between senses of a word.
这些非常精细的细微差别在一个词的意义之间。
So, what sort of saying for good, um,
那么，什么样的好说，嗯，
there's what some sensors where it's a noun, right?
有些传感器就是名词，对吧？
That's where you sort of,
那是你的地方，
I bought some goods for my trip, right?
我为我的旅行买了一些货，对吗？
So, that's sort of, um,
所以，那是那种，嗯，
one of these noun sensors like this one I guess.
我猜这些名词传感器就像这样一个。
Um, then there are adjective sensors and it's trying to
嗯，然后有形容词传感器，它正在尝试
distinguish- there's a basic adjective sense of good being good,
区分 - 有一个基本的形容词良好的感觉，
and then in certain, um, sensors,
然后在某些，嗯，传感器，
there are these extended sensors of good in different directions.
这些扩展的传感器在不同方向上都很好。
So, I guess this is good in the sense of beneficial, um,
所以，我觉得从有益的意义上说这是好的，嗯，
and this one is sort of person who is respectable or something.
这个人是一个受人尊敬的人。
He's a good man or something like that, right?
他是个好人或类似的东西，对吗？
So, um, but you know,
所以，嗯，但你知道，
part of what's kind of makes us
是什么让我们的一部分
think very problematic and practice to use is it tries to make
认为非常有问题，并且尝试使用它是试图制造的
all these very fine-grain differences between sensors that are a human being can
所有这些人类传感器之间的细微差别都可以
barely understand the difference between them um, and relate to.
勉强理解他们之间的区别，并与之相关。
Um, so you can then do other things with WordNet.
嗯，所以你可以用WordNet做其他事情。
So, this bit of code you can sort of well walk up and is a kind of hierarchy.
所以，这些代码你可以很好地走，并且是一种层次结构。
So, it's kinda like a traditional, um, database.
所以，它有点像传统的嗯数据库。
So, if I start with a panda and say- [NOISE] if I start with a panda.
所以，如果我从一只熊猫开始说 - 如果我从一只熊猫开始说 -  [NOISE]。
Um, and walk up, um,
嗯，走吧，嗯，
the pandas are [inaudible].
大熊猫是[音频不清晰]。
Maybe you'd guys to bio which are carnivores,
也许你们是生物学的食肉动物，
placentals, mammals, blah, blah, blah.
胎盘，哺乳动物，等等，等等等等。
Okay, so, um, that's the kind of stuff you can get out to- out of WordNet.
好吧，那么，嗯，这就是你可以从WordNet中获得的东西。
Um, you know, in practice WordNet has been.
嗯，你知道，在实践中WordNet一直都是。
Everyone sort of used to use it because it gave
每个人都习惯使用它，因为它给了
you some sort of sense of the meaning of the word.
你对某个词的含义有某种意义。
But you know it's also sort of well-known.
但是你知道它也是众所周知的。
It never worked that well.
它从来没有那么好用。
Um, so you know that sort of the synonym sets miss a lot of nuance.
嗯，所以你知道那种同义词集错过了很多细微差别。
So, you know one of the synonym sets for good has
所以，你知道一个好的同义词集
proficient in it and good sort of like proficient
精通它，好像精通
but doesn't proficient have some more connotations and nuance?
但是不熟练有一些内涵和细微差别？
I think it does.
我认为确实如此。
Um, WordNet like most hand built resources is sort of very incomplete.
嗯，WordNet像大多数手工制作的资源一样非常不完整。
So, as soon as you're coming to new meanings of words,
所以，只要你想要新的含义，
or new words and slang words,
或者新词和俚语，
well then, that gives you nothing.
那么，那什么都没给你。
Um, it's sort of built with human labor,
嗯，它是用人工建造的，
um, in ways that you know it's hard to sort of create and adapt.
嗯，以你知道的方式很难创造和适应。
And in particular, what we want to focus on is,
特别是，我们要关注的是，
seems like a basic thing you'd like to do with words and it's actually at least
看起来像是你想用文字做的基本事情，实际上至少是这样
understand similarities and relations between the meaning of words.
理解词语意义之间的相似性和关系。
And it turns out that you know WordNet doesn't actually do that that well
事实证明，你知道WordNet实际上并没有这么做
because it just has these sort of fixed discrete synonym sets.
因为它只有这些固定的离散同义词集。
So, if you have a words in a synonym said that there's
所以，如果你有一个同义词中的单词说有
sort of a synonym and maybe not exactly the same meaning,
一种同义词，可能不完全相同，
they're not in the same synonyms set,
它们不在同一个同义词集中，
you kind of can't really measure the partial resemblance as a meaning for them.
你有点无法将部分相似性视为对他们的意义。
So, if something like good and marvelous aren't in the same synonym set,
所以，如果好的和奇妙的东西不在同一个同义词集中，
but there's something that they share in common that you'd like to represent.
但是他们有一些你想要代表的共同点。
Okay. So, um, that's kinda turn to lead into
好的。所以，嗯，这有点转向
us wanting to do something different and better for word meaning.
我们想要做一些不同的事情，更好地理解词义。
And, um, before getting there I just sort of wanna again sort
而且，嗯，在到达那里之前我只想再次排序
of build a little from traditional NLP.
从传统的NLP构建一点点。
So, traditional NLP in the context of this course sort of means
所以，传统的NLP在本课程的背景下有点手段
Natural Language Processing up until approximately 2012.
自然语言处理直到大约2012年。
There were some earlier antecedents but as basically, um,
有一些早期的前因，但基本上，嗯，
in 2013 that things really began to change with
在2013年，事情真的开始发生变化
people starting to use neural net style representations for natural language processing.
人们开始使用神经网络风格表示来进行自然语言处理。
So, up until 2012,
所以，直到2012年，
um, standardly you know we had words.
嗯，标准的是你知道我们有话语。
They are just words. So, we had hotel conference motel.
他们只是言语。所以，我们有酒店会议汽车旅馆。
They were words, and we'd have you know lexicons and put words into our model.
他们是单词，我们让你知道词典并在我们的模型中加入单词。
Um, and in neural networks land this is referred to as a localist representation.
嗯，在神经网络中，这被称为地方主义代表。
I'll come back to those terms again next time.
我下次再回来谈谈这些条款。
But that's sort of meaning that for any concept there's sort of one particular,
但这有点意思，对于任何概念都有一个特别的，
um, place which is the word hotel or the word motel.
嗯，这是酒店或汽车旅馆这个词的地方。
A way of thinking about that is to think
一种思考方式就是思考
about what happens when you build a machine learning model.
关于构建机器学习模型时会发生什么。
So, if you have a categorical variable like you have words with the choice of word
所以，如果你有一个分类变量，就像你有单词选择的单词
and you want to stick that into some kind of classifier in a Machine Learning Model,
并且你想在机器学习模型中将其粘贴到某种分类器中，
somehow you have to code that categorical variable,
不知何故，你必须编码那个分类变量，
and the standard way of doing it is that you code it by having
这样做的标准方法是你通过拥有它来编码
different levels of the variable which means that you have a vector,
不同级别的变量意味着你有一个向量，
and you have, this is the word house.
你有，这就是房子这个词。
This is the word cat. This is the word dog.
这是单词cat。这就是单词dog。
This is the word some chairs.
这是一些椅子这个词。
This is the word agreeable.
这是一个令人愉快的词。
This is the word something else.
这是别的东西。
This is the word, um,
这个词，嗯，
hotel, um, and this is another word for something different, right?
酒店，嗯，这是另一个不同的词，对吗？
So that you have put a one at the position
所以你已经把一个放在了这个位置
and neural net land we call these one-hot vectors,
和神经网络我们称之为一个热的向量，
and so these might be, ah,
所以这些可能是，啊，
one-hot vectors for hotel and motel.
酒店和汽车旅馆的单热矢量。
So, there are a couple of things that are bad here.
所以，这里有一些不好的事情。
Um, the one that's sort of, ah,
嗯，那个，啊，
practical nuisance is you know languages have a lot of words.
实际上令人讨厌的是你知道语言有很多单词。
Ah, so, it's sort of one of those dictionaries that you might have still had in
啊，那么，它可能是你可能还有的那些词典之一
school that you probably have about 250,000 words in them.
学校你可能有大约250,000字。
But you know, if you start getting into
但是你知道，如果你开始进入
more technical and scientific English it's easy to get to a million words.
更加技术和科学的英语很容易达到一百万字。
I mean, actually the number of words that you have in a language, um,
我的意思是，实际上你在一种语言中拥有的单词数量，嗯，
like English is actually infinite because we have
像英语一样，实际上是无限的因为我们有
these processes which are called derivational morphology,
这些过程称为衍生形态学，
um, where you can make more words by adding endings onto existing words.
嗯，你可以通过在现有单词上添加结尾来创造更多单词。
So, you know you can start with something like paternalist,
所以，你知道你可以从家长式的东西开始，
fatherly, and then you can sort of say from maternal,
父亲，然后你可以从母亲那里说，
you can say paternalist, or paternalistic,
你可以说是家长式的，或家长式的，
paternalism and pa- I did it paternalistically.
家长作风和pa-我做了家长式的。
Right? Now all of these ways that you can bake bigger words by adding more stuff into it.
对？现在所有这些方法都可以通过添加更多内容来烘焙更大的单词。
Um, and so really you end up with an infinite space of words.
嗯，所以你最终会得到无限的文字空间。
Um, yeah. So that's a minor problem, right?
嗯，是的这是一个小问题，对吧？
We have very big vectors if we want to represent a sensible size vocabulary.
如果我们想要表示合理的大小词汇，我们有很大的向量。
Um, but there's a much bigger problem than that, which is, well,
嗯，但是有一个更大的问题，那就是，嗯，
precisely what we want to do all the time, is we want to,
正是我们想要一直做的，是我们想要的，
sort of, understand relationships and the meaning of words.
某种，理解关系和词语的意义。
So, you know, an obvious example of this is web search.
所以，你知道，一个明显的例子就是网络搜索。
So, if I do a search for Seattle motel,
所以，如果我搜索西雅图汽车旅馆，
it'd be useful if it also showed me results that had
如果它也向我展示了结果，那将是有用的
Seattle hotel on the page and vice versa because,
西雅图酒店在页面上，反之亦然，因为，
you know, hotels and motels pretty much the same thing.
你知道，酒店和汽车旅馆几乎是一回事。
Um, but, you know, if we have these one-hot vectors like we had before they have
嗯，但是，你知道，如果我们拥有像我们之前那样的热门载体
no s- similarity relationship between them, right?
他们之间没有相似的关系吧？
So, in math terms,
所以，在数学方面，
these two vectors are orthogonal.
这两个向量是正交的。
No similarity relationship between them.
他们之间没有相似关系。
Um, and so you,
嗯，你呢，
kind of, get nowhere.
有点，无处可去。
Now, you know, there are things that you could do,
现在，你知道，有些事你可以做，
I- I just showed you WordNet's.
我 - 我刚给你看了WordNet的。
WordNet's shows you some synonyms and stuff.
WordNet向您展示了一些同义词和内容。
So that might help a bit.
所以这可能会有所帮助。
There are other things you could do.
你还可以做其他事情。
You could sort of say, well wait,
你可以说，等等，
why don't we just build up a big table where we have a big table of,
为什么我们不建立一个大桌子，我们有一个大桌子，
um, word similarities, and we could work with that.
嗯，有相似之处，我们可以解决这个问题。
And, you know, people used to try and do that, right?
而且，你知道，人们过去常常尝试这样做，对吗？
You know, that's sort of what Google did in 2005 or something.
你知道，这就是谷歌2005年所做的事情。
You know, it had word similarity tables.
你知道，它有单词相似表。
The problem with doing that is you know,
这样做的问题是你知道的，
we were talking about how maybe we want 500,000 words.
我们在谈论我们可能想要500,000个单词。
And if you want to build up then a word similarity table out
如果你想建立一个单词相似表
of our pairs of words from one-hot representations,
从一个热门的陈述中我们的一对词，
um, you- that means that the size of that table,
嗯，你 - 这意味着那张桌子的大小，
as my math is pretty bad,
因为我的数学非常糟糕，
is it 2,5 trillion?
是2,5万亿？
It's some very big number of cells in your similarity, um, matrix.
你的相似性，嗯，矩阵中有一些非常大的细胞。
So that's almost impossible to do.
所以这几乎是不可能的。
So, what we're gonna instead do is explore a method in which,
所以，我们要做的是探索一种方法，其中，
um, we are going to represent words as vectors,
嗯，我们要将单词表示为向量，
in a way I'll show you just, um,
在某种程度上，我会告诉你，嗯，
a minute in such a way that just the representation of
以这种方式表达的一分钟
a word gives you their similarity with no further work.
一句话给你的相似之处，没有进一步的工作。
Okay. And so that's gonna lead into these different ideas.
好的。因此，这将导致这些不同的想法。
So, I mentioned before denotational semantics.
所以，我之前提到了指称语义。
Here's another idea for representing the meaning of words,
这是表示单词含义的另一个想法，
um, which is called distributional semantics.
嗯，这叫做分布式语义。
And so the idea of distributional semantics is, well,
因此，分布式语义的概念是，
how are we going to represent the meaning of a word is by looking at the contexts,
我们如何通过观察背景来表示一个词的意义，
um, in which it appears.
嗯，它出现了。
So, this is a picture of JR Firth who was a British linguist.
所以，这是一张英国语言学家JR Firth的照片。
Um, he's famous for this saying,
嗯，他这个说法很有名，
"You shall know a word by the company it keeps."
“你应该知道它所保留的公司的一句话。”
Um, but another person who's very famous for developing this notion of meaning is, um,
嗯，但另一个因发展这种意义概念而闻名的人是，嗯，
the philosopher Ludwig- Ludwig Wittgenstein in his later writings,
哲学家路德维希 - 路德维希·维特根斯坦在后来的着作中，
which he referred to as a use theory of meeting- meaning.
他称之为会议意义的使用理论。
Well, actually he's- he used some big German word that I don't know,
好吧，实际上他 - 他使用了一些我不知道的德语大词，
but, um, we'll call it a use theory of meaning.
但是，嗯，我们称之为意义的使用理论。
And, you know, essentially the point was, well, you know,
而且，你知道，基本上重点是，你知道，
if you can explain every- if- if you can
如果你可以解释每一个 - 如果可以的话
explain what contexts it's correct to use a certain word,
解释使用某个单词是正确的，
versus in what contexts would be the wrong word to use,
与在什么情况下使用的错误词相比，
this maybe gives you bad memories of doing English in high school,
这可能会让你忘记在高中做英语，
when people said, ah, that's the wrong word to use there,
当人们说啊，这是错误的用法，
um, well, then you understand the meaning of the word, right?
嗯，那么你理解这个词的意思吧？
Um, and so that's the idea of distributional semantics.
嗯，这就是分布式语义的概念。
And it's been- so one of the most successful ideas in
它一直是最成功的想法之一
modern statistical NLP because it gives you a great way to learn about word meaning.
现代统计NLP，因为它为您提供了一个学习词义的好方法。
And so what we're gonna do is we're going to say,
所以我们要做的就是说，
haha, I want to know what the word banking means.
哈哈，我想知道银行这个词是什么意思。
So, I'm gonna grab a lot of texts,
所以，我要抓很多文本，
which is easy to do now when we have the World Wide Web,
当我们拥有万维网时，这很容易做到
I'll find lots of sentences where the word banking is used,
我会发现许多句子都使用了bank这个词，
Government debt problems turning into banking crises as happened in 2009.
政府债务问题转变为2009年发生的银行业危机。
And both these- I'm just going to say all of
这两个 - 我只想说全部
this stuff is the meaning of the word banking.
这个东西是银行这个词的意思。
Um, that those are the contexts in which the word banking is used.
嗯，这些是使用银行业务这个词的背景。
And that seems like very simple and perhaps even not quite right idea,
这看起来很简单，甚至可能不太正确，
but it turns out to be a very usable idea that does a great job at capturing meaning.
但事实证明这是一个非常有用的想法，可以很好地捕捉意义。
And so what we're gonna do is say rather than
所以我们要做的就是说而不是
our old localist representation we're now gonna
我们现在要去的旧地方主义代表
represent words in what we call a distributed representation.
代表我们称之为分布式表示的单词。
And so, for the distributed representation we're still going
因此，对于分布式表示，我们仍然会继续
to [NOISE] represent the meaning of a word as a numeric vector.
to [NOISE]表示单词作为数字向量的含义。
But now we're going to say that the meaning of each word is,
但现在我们要说每个单词的含义是，
ah, smallish vector, um,
啊，小矢量，嗯，
but it's going to be a dense vector where by all of the numbers are non-zero.
但它将是一个密集的向量，其中所有数字都是非零的。
So the meaning of banking is going to be
银行业的意义就在于此
distributed over the dim- dimensions of this vector.
分布在这个向量的暗淡维度上。
Um, now, my vector here is of dimension nine because I want to keep the slide, um, nice.
嗯，现在，我的向量是九维，因为我想保持幻灯片，嗯，很好。
Um, life isn't quite that good in practice.
嗯，生活在实践中并不是那么好。
When we do this we use a larger dimensionality,
当我们这样做时，我们使用更大的维度，
kinda, solid the minimum that people use is 50.
有点，坚固，人们使用的最低限度是50。
Um, a typical number that you might use on your laptop is
嗯，你可能在笔记本电脑上使用的典型号码是
300 if you want to really max out performance,
300，如果你想真正最大化性能，
um, maybe 1,000, 2,000, 4,000.
嗯，可能是1,000,2,000,4,000。
But, you know, nevertheless [NOISE] orders of magnitude is
但是，你知道，然而[NOISE]数量级是
smaller compared to a length 500,000 vector.
与长度为500,000的向量相比更小。
Okay. So we have words with their vector representations.
好的。所以我们有他们的矢量表示的单词。
And so since each word is going to have a vector, um,
因为每个单词都会有一个向量，嗯，
representation we then have a vector space in which we can place all of the words.
表示我们然后有一个向量空间，我们可以在其中放置所有单词。
Um, and that's completely unreadable, um,
嗯，这完全不可读，嗯，
but if you zoom into the vector space it's still completely unreadable.
但如果你放大矢量空间，它仍然是完全不可读的。
But if you zoom in a bit further,
但如果你进一步放大，
um, you can find different parts of this space.
嗯，你可以找到这个空间的不同部分。
So here's the part that where countries attending to,
所以这是国家参加的部分，
um, exist Japanese, German,
嗯，存在日语，德语，
French, Russian, British Australian American,
法国，俄罗斯，英国澳大利亚人，
um, France, Britain, Germany et cetera.
嗯，法国，英国，德国等。
And you can shift over to a different part of the space.
你可以转移到空间的不同部分。
So here's a part of the space where various verbs are,
所以这里是各种动词的空间的一部分，
so has have, had, been, be.
所以已经，过去，过去了。
Oops. Um, um, [inaudible] be always was where.
哎呀。嗯，[听不清]总是在哪里。
You can even see that some morphological forms are grouping together,
你甚至可以看到一些形态形式在一起组合，
and things that sort of go together like say,
和那些喜欢说话的东西一样
think expect to things that take those, kind of, compliment.
我希望能够接受那些带有那些，有点赞美的东西。
He said or thought something.
他说或想到了什么。
Um, they group together.
嗯，他们聚在一起。
Now, what am I actually showing you here?
现在，我在这里向你展示了什么？
Um, you know, really this was built from,
嗯，你知道，这真的是建立在，
ah, 100 dimensional word vectors.
啊，100维词向量。
And there is this problem is really hard to visualize 100 dimensional word vectors.
并且存在这个问题实际上难以可视化100维单词向量。
So, what is actually happening here is these, um,
那么，这里真正发生的是这些，嗯，
100 dimensional word vectors are being projected down into two-dimensions,
100维单词向量被投射到二维，
and you're so- seeing the two-dimensional view,
你看到了二维视图，
which I'll get back to later.
我稍后会回来的。
Um, so, on the one hand, um,
嗯，一方面，嗯，
whenever you see these pictures you should hold on to
每当你看到这些照片时，你都应该坚持下去
the your wallet because there's a huge amount of
你的钱包，因为有大量的钱包
detail on the original vector space that got completely killed and went away, um,
完全杀死并离开的原始矢量空间的细节，嗯，
in the 2D projection,
在2D投影中，
and indeed some of what push things together in the 2D,
确实有些东西在2D中推动了一起，
um, projection may really, really,
嗯，投影可能真的，真的，
really misrepresent what's in the original space.
真的歪曲了原始空间里的东西。
Um, but even looking at these 2D representations,
嗯，但即使看这些2D表示，
the overall feeling is,
整体感觉是，
my gosh this actually sort of works, doesn't it?
我的天哪这实际上有点作品，不是吗？
Um, we can sort of see similarities, um, between words.
嗯，我们可以在文字之间看到相似之处。
Okay. So, um, ha- so that was the idea of what we want to do.
好的。那么，嗯，那么这就是我们想要做的事情的想法。
Um, the next part, um,
嗯，下一部分，嗯，
is then how do we actually go about doing it?
那么我们实际上是如何去做的呢？
I'll pause for breath for half a minute.
我会停下来呼吸半分钟。
Has anyone got a question they're dying to ask?
有没有人有一个他们想要问的问题？
[NOISE] Yeah.
[NOISE]是的
Where were the- the vectors is each, um,
那些载体在哪里，嗯，
had a different order in each contact,
每个联系人都有不同的顺序，
like, say the first decimal vector,
比如，说第一个十进制矢量，
second decimal vector, are those standard
第二个十进制向量，是那些标准
across all theory or people choose them themselves?
所有理论或人们自己选择它们？
Um, they're not standards across NLP um and they're not chosen at all.
嗯，他们不是NLP的标准，他们根本就没有被选中。
So what we're gonna present is a learning algorithm.
所以我们要呈现的是学习算法。
So where we just sort of shuffle in lots of text
所以我们只是在很多文本中进行洗牌
and miraculously these word vectors come out.
奇迹般地，这些单词向量出来了。
And so the l- learning algorithm itself decides the dimensions.
因此，l-学习算法本身决定了维度。
But um that actually reminds me of something I sort of meant to say which was yeah,
但是，这实际上让我想起了一些我想说的是什么，是的，
I mean, since this is a vector space,
我的意思是，因为这是一个向量空间，
in some sense the dimensions over the arbitrary right,
在某种意义上，任意权利的维度，
because you can you know just have your basis vectors in
因为你可以知道你的基础载体
any different direction and you could sort of re-represent,
任何不同的方向，你可以重新代表，
um the words in the vector space with a different set of basics,
嗯，向量空间中的单词具有不同的基础，
basis vectors and it'd be exactly the same vector space
基矢量，它是完全相同的矢量空间
just sort of rotate around to your new um, vectors.
只是旋转到你的新嗯，矢量。
So, you know, you shouldn't read too much into the sort of elements.
所以，你知道，你不应该过多地阅读这些元素。
So, it actually turns out that because of the way a lot of
所以，事实证明，由于很多方式
deep learning um operations work,
深入学习运营工作，
some things they do, do element-wise.
他们做的一些事情，做元素。
So that the dimensions do actually tend to get some meaning to them it turns out.
事实证明，维度实际上往往会对他们产生一些意义。
But um, though I think I really wanted to say was,
但是嗯，虽然我觉得我真想说的是，
that you know one thing we can just think of is how close things
你知道我们可以想到的一件事是多么接近
are in the vector space and that's
是在向量空间，那是
a notion of meaning similarity that we are going to exploit.
我们将要利用的意义相似性概念。
But you might hope that you get more than that,
但是你可能希望得到更多，
and you might actually think that there's meaning in
你可能会认为它有意义
different dimensions and directions in the word vector space.
词向量空间中的不同维度和方向。
And the answer to that is there is and I'll come back to that a bit later.
答案就是这样，我稍后会再回过头来。
Okay. Um, so in some sense this thing that had
好的。嗯，所以从某种意义上讲，这件事情已经发生了
the biggest impact um in sort of turning the world of
影响世界的最大影响
NLP in a neural networks direction was that picture.
神经网络方向的NLP就是那张照片。
Um, was this um algorithm that um
嗯，这是你的算法嗯
Thomas Mikolov came up with in 2013 called the word2vec algorithm.
Thomas Mikolov在2013年提出了word2vec算法。
So it wasn't the first work and having distributed representations of words.
因此，这不是第一部作品，而是分发了单词的表示。
So there was older work from Yoshua Bengio that went
因此，来自Yoshua Bengio的旧工作已经开始了
back to about the sort of turn on the millennium,
回到关于千禧年的转折，
that somehow it's sort of hadn't really sort of hit the world over their head and had
不知怎的，这种情况并没有真正触及世界的头脑而已
a huge impact and has really sort of Thomas Mikolov showed this very simple,
一个巨大的影响，真的有一点托马斯米科洛夫表明这很简单，
very scalable way of learning
非常可扩展的学习方式
vector representations of um words and that sort of really opened the flood gates.
um词的矢量表示和那种真正打开了洪水门。
And so that's the algorithm that I'm going to um show now.
所以这就是我现在要展示的算法。
Okay. So the idea of this algorithm is you start with a big pile of text.
好的。所以这个算法的想法是从一大堆文本开始。
Um, so wherever you find you know web pages on newspaper articles or something,
嗯，所以，只要你发现你知道报纸上的文章或其他东西的网页，
a lot of continuous text, right?
很多连续的文字吧？
Actual sentences because we want to learn wo- word meaning context.
实际的句子，因为我们想要学习含义的语境。
Um, NLP people call a large pile of text a corpus.
嗯，NLP人称一大堆文本为语料库。
And I mean that's just the Latin word for body, right?
我的意思是，这只是拉丁语中的身体，对吗？
It's a body of text.
这是一个文本正文。
Important things to note if you want to seem really educated is in Latin,
如果你想要真正受过教育，重要的事情是拉丁语，
this is a fourth declensions noun.
这是第四个变种名词。
So the plural of corpus is corpora.
所以语料库的复数是语料库。
And whereas if you say
而如果你说的话
core Pi everyone will know that you didn't study Latin in high school.
核心Pi每个人都会知道你没有在高中学习拉丁语。
[LAUGHTER] Um, okay.
[大笑]嗯，好的。
Um, so right- so we then want to say that every word um
嗯，好吧 - 所以我们想说每个字嗯
in a- in a fixed vocabulary which would just be
在一个固定的词汇表中
the vocabulary the corpus is um represented by a vector.
语料库的词汇由向量表示。
And we just start those vectors off as random vectors.
我们只是将这些向量作为随机向量启动。
And so then what we're going to do is do
那么我们要做的就是做
this big iterative algorithm where we go through each position in the text.
这个大迭代算法，我们遍历文本中的每个位置。
We say, here's a word in the text.
我们说，这是文中的一个词。
Let's look at the words around it and what we're going to want to do is say well,
让我们来看看它周围的单词以及我们想要做的是说得好，
the meaning of a word is its contexts of use.
一个词的意思是它的使用背景。
So we want the representation of the word
所以我们想要这个词的表示
in the middle to be able to predict the words that are
在中间能够预测那些词
around it and so we're gonna achieve that by moving the position of the word vector.
围绕它，所以我们将通过移动单词向量的位置来实现这一点。
And we just repeat that a billion times and
我们只重复十亿次
somehow a miracle occurs and outcomes at the end we have
不知怎的，奇迹发生了，最后我们得到了结果
a word vector space that looks like a picture I showed where it has
一个单词矢量空间看起来像我展示它所在的图片
a good meaning of word meet good representation of word meaning.
词语的良好含义符合词义的良好表现。
So slightly more, um,
那么多一点，嗯，
um, slightly more um graphically right.
嗯，稍微更正好用图形表示。
So here's the situation.
所以情况就是这样。
So we've got part of our corpus problems turning into banking crisis,
所以我们的部分语料库问题变成了银行危机，
and so what we want to say is well,
所以我们想说的很好，
we want to know the meaning of the word into and so we're going to hope that
我们想知道这个词的含义，所以我们希望如此
its representation can be used in a way that'll
它的表示可以以一种方式使用
make precise to predict what words appear in
准确地预测出现的单词
the context of into because that's the meaning of into.
进入的背景因为那是进入的意义。
And so we're going to try and make those predictions,
所以我们将尝试做出这些预测，
see how well we can predict and then change
看看我们如何预测然后改变
the vector representations of words in a way that we can do that prediction better.
单词的向量表示，我们可以更好地进行预测。
And then once we've dealt with into,
然后，一旦我们处理了，
we just go onto the next word and we say,
我们只是谈谈下一个词，我们说，
okay, let's take banking as the word.
好的，我们以银行业为单位。
The meaning of banking is predicting the contexts in which banking occurs.
银行业的含义是预测银行业发生的背景。
Here's one context.
这是一个背景。
Let's try and predict these words that occur around banking and
让我们试着预测银行和银行周围发生的这些话
see how we do and then we'll move on again from there.
看看我们如何做，然后我们将再次从那里继续前进。
Okay. Um, sounds easy so far.
好的。嗯，到目前为止听起来很容易。
Um, [NOISE] now we go on and sort of do a bit more stuff.
嗯，[NOISE]现在我们继续做更多的事情。
Okay. So overall, we have a big long corpus of capital T words.
好的。总的来说，我们有一大笔资本T字。
So if we have a whole lot of documents we just concatenate them all together and we say,
因此，如果我们有大量文档，我们只是将它们连接在一起，我们说，
okay, here's a billion words,
好的，这是十亿字，
and so big long list of words.
这么长的单词列表。
And so what we're gonna do,
那么我们要做什么，
is for the first um product we're going to sort of
是我们要用的第一款产品
go through all the words and then for the second product,
仔细阅读所有的话，然后是第二个产品，
we're gonna say- we're gonna choose some fixed size window, you know,
我们要说 - 我们要选择一些固定尺寸的窗户，你知道，
it might be five words on each side or something and we're going to try and
它可能是每个方面的五个字或什么，我们将尝试和
predict the 10 words that are around that center word.
预测围绕该中心词的10个单词。
And we're going to predict in the sense of trying to
我们将在尝试的意义上预测
predict that word given the center word.
预测这个词给出了中心词。
That's our probability model.
这是我们的概率模型。
And so if we multiply all those things together,
所以，如果我们将所有这些东西混合在一起，
that's our model likelihood is how good a job it
这是我们的模型可能性是一个多么好的工作
does at predicting the words around every word.
预测每个单词周围的单词。
And that model likelihood is going to depend
而这种模式可能性将取决于
on the parameters of our model which we write as theta.
关于我们写成theta的模型的参数。
And in this particular model,
在这个特定的模型中，
the only parameters in it is actually
其中唯一的参数实际上是
going to be the vector representations we give the words.
将成为我们给出的单词的向量表示。
The model has absolutely no other parameters to it.
该模型绝对没有其他参数。
So, we're just going to say we're representing
所以，我们只是说我们要代表
a word with a vector in a vector space and that
一个单词与向量空间中的向量和那
representation of it is its meaning and we're then going to be able to
它的代表是它的意义，然后我们就能够
use that to predict what other words occur in a way I'm about to show you.
用它来预测其他单词会以我即将向您展示的方式出现。
Okay. So, um, that's our likelihood and so what we do in all of
好的。所以，嗯，这是我们的可能性，所以我们在所有方面做了什么
these models is we sort of define an objective function and then we're going to be,
这些模型是我们定义一个目标函数，然后我们将，
I want to come up with vector representations of words in
我想提出单词的矢量表示
such a way as to minimize our objective function.
这样可以最大限度地减少我们的目标函数。
Um, so objective function is basically the same as what's on the top half of the slide,
嗯，所以客观功能基本上与幻灯片上半部分相同，
but we change a couple of things.
但我们改变了一些事情。
We stick a minus sign in front of it so we can do minimization rather than maximization.
我们在它前面贴了一个减号，这样我们就可以做到最小化而不是最大化。
Completely arbitrary makes no difference.
完全随意没有区别。
Um, we stick a one and T in front of it,
嗯，我们在它前面贴一个和T，
so that we're working out the sort of average
所以我们正在努力达到平均水平
as of a goodness of predicting for each choice of center word.
作为预测每个中心词的选择的好处。
Again, that sort of makes no difference but it kinda keeps the scale of
再一次，这种情况没有区别，但它有点保持规模
things ah not dependent on the size of the corpus.
事情啊不依赖于语料库的大小。
Um, the bit that's actually important is we stick a log in front of
嗯，实际上重要的是我们在前面贴上一个日志
the function that was up there um because it turns out that everything always gets nice.
在那里的功能，因为事实证明一切都变得很好。
So when you stick logs and find the products
所以当你粘贴日志并找到产品时
um when you're doing things like optimization.
嗯，当你做优化这样的事情。
So, when we do that we then got a log of
所以，当我们这样做时，我们得到了一个日志
all these products which will allow us to turn things you know,
所有这些产品都可以让我们转变你所知道的东西，
into a sums of the log of this probability
成为这个概率的对数的总和
and we'll go through that again um in just a minute.
我们会在一分钟内再次讨论这个问题。
Okay. Um, and so if we can mi- if we can change
好的。嗯，如果我们可以，我们可以改变
our vector representations of these words so as to minimize this J of theta,
我们对这些词的矢量表示，以便最小化这个the of the of the of the of the the
that means we'll be good at predicting words in the context of another word.
这意味着我们善于在另一个词的语境中预测单词。
So then, that all sounded good but it was all
那么，这一切听起来都不错，但一切都好
dependent on having this probability function where you wanna
依赖于你想要的概率函数
predict the probability of a word in
预测一个单词的概率
the context given the center word and the question is,
给出中心词和问题的上下文是，
how can you possibly do that?
你怎么可能那样做？
Um, well um, remember what I said is actually our model is just gonna
嗯，嗯，记住我所说的实际上我们的模型就是这样
have vector representations of words and that was the only parameters of the model.
有单词的矢量表示，这是模型的唯一参数。
Now, that's, that's almost true.
现在，那就是，这几乎是真的。
It's not quite true.
这不是真的。
Um, we actually cheat slightly.
嗯，我们实际上有点作弊。
Since we actually propose two vector representations for
因为我们实际上提出了两个向量表示
each word and this makes it simpler to do this.
每个单词，这使得这样做更简单。
Um, you cannot do this,
嗯，你不能这样做，
there are ways to get around it but this is the simplest way to do it.
有办法解决它，但这是最简单的方法。
So we have one vector for word when it's the center word that's predicting
因此，当它是预测的中心词时，我们有一个单词向量
other words but we have a second vector for each word when it's a context word,
换句话说，但是当它是一个上下文单词时，每个单词都有第二个向量，
so that's one of the words in context.
这是上下文中的一个词。
So for each word type,
所以对于每个单词类型，
we have these two vectors as center word, as context word.
我们将这两个向量作为中心词，作为上下文词。
Um, so then we're gonna work out this probability of a word in the context,
嗯，那么我们将在上下文中找出一个单词的概率，
given the center word,
给出中心词，
purely in terms of these vectors and the way we do it is with this equation right here,
纯粹就这些向量而言，我们这样做的方式就是这个等式，
which I'll explain more in just a moment.
我稍后会解释一下。
So we're still on exactly the same situation, right?
所以我们仍然处于完全相同的情况，对吧？
That we're wanting to work out probabilities of
我们想要弄清楚的可能性
words occurring in the context of our center word.
在我们的中心词语中出现的单词。
So the center word is C and the context words represented with
因此，中心词是C，用上下文词表示
O and these [inaudible] slide notation but sort of,
O和这些[听不清]幻灯片符号，但有点，
we're basically saying there's one kind of
我们基本上说有一种
vector for center words is a different kind of vector
中心词的矢量是一种不同的矢量
for context words and we're gonna work out this probabilistic prediction um,
对于上下文单词，我们要解决这个概率预测，
in terms of these word vectors.
就这些单词向量而言。
Okay. So how can we do that?
好的。那我们怎么做呢？
Well, the way we do it is with this um,
那么，我们这样做的方式就是这个，
formula here which is the sort of shape that you see over and over again um,
这里的公式是你一遍又一遍看到的那种形状嗯，
in deep learning with categorical staff.
在深入学习与分类员工。
So for the very center bit of it,
所以对于它的中心位，
the bit in orange are more the same thing occurs in the um, denominator.
橙色的位是更多相同的东西发生在嗯，分母。
What we're doing there is calculating a dot product.
我们在那里做的是计算点积。
So, we're gonna go through the components of our vector and we're gonna
所以，我们要经历我们的矢量组件，我们会
multiply them together and that means if um,
将它们相乘，这意味着如果嗯，
different words have B components of the same sign,
不同的单词有相同符号的B组成部分，
plus or minus, in the same positions,
加或减，在相同的位置，
the dot product will be big and if
点积将很大，如果
they have different signs or one is big and one is small,
他们有不同的标志，或者一个很大，一个很小，
the dot product will be a lot smaller.
点积将小很多。
So that orange part directly calculates uh,
所以橙色部分直接计算呃，
sort of a similarity between words where
单词之间的相似之处
the similarity is the sort of vectors looking the same, right?
相似性是那种看起来相同的向量，对吧？
Um, and so that's the heart of it, right?
嗯，这就是它的核心，对吧？
So we're gonna have words that have similar vectors,
所以我们会有类似载体的单词，
IS close together in the vector space have similar meaning.
在向量空间中靠近在一起具有相似的含义。
Um, so for the rest of it- um,
嗯，对于其余部分，嗯，
so the next thing we do is take that number and put an X around it.
所以我们接下来要做的就是拿这个数字并在它周围放一个X.
So, um, the exponential has
所以，嗯，指数有
this nice property that no matter what number you stick into it,
这个不错的属性，无论你坚持到底是什么号码，
because the dot product might be positive or negative,
因为点积可能是正数或负数，
it's gonna come out as a positive number and if
它会作为一个正数出来，如果
we eventually wanna get a probability, um, that's really good.
我们最终想得到一个概率，嗯，这真的很好。
If we have positive numbers and not negative numbers, um, so that's good.
如果我们有正数而不是负数，那么这很好。
Um, then the third part of which is the bid in blue is we wanted to have
嗯，其中第三部分是蓝色的出价是我们想要的
probabilities and probabilities are meant to add up to
概率和概率意味着加起来
one and so we do that in the standard, dumbest possible way.
一个，所以我们以标准，最愚蠢的方式做到这一点。
We sum up what this quantity is,
我们总结一下这个数量是多少，
that every different word in our vocabulary and we divide through by
我们的词汇中的每一个不同的词都是我们分过来的
it and so that normalizes things and turns them into a probability distribution.
它使事物正常化并将它们变成概率分布。
Yeah, so there's sort of in practice,
是的，所以有一些实践，
there are two parts.
有两个部分。
There's the orange part which is this idea of using
橙色部分是这个使用的想法
dot product and a vector space as our similarity measure between words
点积和向量空间作为词之间的相似性度量
and then the second part is all the rest of it where we feed it
然后第二部分是我们喂它的所有其余部分
through what we refer to a news all the time as a softmax distribution.
通过我们所说的新闻作为softmax发行版。
So the two parts of the expen normalizing gives you a softmax distribution.
因此，费用标准化的两个部分为您提供softmax分布。
Um, and softmax functions will sort of map any numbers into
嗯，softmax函数会将任何数字映射到
a probability distribution always for the two reasons that I gave and so,
概率分布总是出于我给出的两个原因，因此，
it's referred to as a softmax um,
它被称为softmax um，
because it works like a softmax, right?
因为它像softmax一样工作，对吧？
So if you have numbers,
所以，如果你有数字，
you could just say what's the max of these numbers, um,
你可以说这些数字的最大值是什么，嗯，
and you know that's sort of a hot- if you sort of map your original numbers into,
而且你知道这有点热 - 如果你将原始数字映射到，
if it's the max of the max and everything else is zero,
如果它是最大值的最大值，其他一切都为零，
that's sort of a hard max.
这是一个很难的最大值。
Um, soft- this is a softmax because the exponenti- you know,
嗯，软 - 这是一个softmax，因为指数 - 你知道，
if you sort of imagine this but- if we just ignore the problem
如果你有点想象这个但是 - 如果我们忽略了这个问题
negative numbers for a moment and you got rid of the exp, um,
一段时间的负数，你摆脱了exp，嗯，
then you'd sort of coming out with
然后你就会出来
a probability distribution but by and large it's so be fairly
一个概率分布，但总的来说它是公平的
flat and wouldn't particularly pick out the max of
平坦，并不会特别挑选出最大值
the different XI numbers whereas when you exponentiate them,
不同的XI数字，而当你取代它们时，
that sort of makes big numbers way bigger and so, this,
那种大数字会变大，所以，这个，
this softmax sort of mainly puts mass where the max's or the couple of max's are.
这种softmax主要是将质量放在最大值或最大值的最大值。
Um, so that's the max part and a soft part is that this isn't
嗯，所以这是最大的部分和软的部分是这不是
a hard decisions still spreads a little bit of probability mass everywhere else.
一个艰难的决定仍然会在其他地方传播一点概率。
Okay, so now we have uh, loss function.
好的，现在我们有呃，失去功能。
We have a loss function with a probability model on the inside that we can
我们有一个损失函数，我们可以在内部使用概率模型
build and so what we want to be able to do is then um,
构建，所以我们想要做的就是嗯，
move our vector representations of words around
移动我们的单词的向量表示
so that they are good at predicting what words occur in the context of other words.
这样他们就能善于预测在其他词语中出现的词语。
Um, and so, at this point what we're gonna do is optimization.
嗯，在这一点上，我们要做的就是优化。
So, we have vector components of different words.
所以，我们有不同单词的向量组件。
We have a very high-dimensional space again but here,
我们再次拥有一个非常高维度的空间，但在这里，
I've just got two for the picture and we're gonna wanna
我刚刚有两张照片，我们想要的
say how- how can we minimize this function and we're going to
说怎么样我们可以最小化这个功能，我们会去
want to jiggle the numbers that are used in the word representations in
想要摆动单词表示中使用的数字
such a way that we're walking down the slope of this space.
这样一种方式，我们走在这个空间的斜坡上。
I walking down the gradient and um,
我走下梯度，嗯，
then we're gonna minimize the function we found good representations for words.
那么我们将最大限度地减少我们找到好的词汇表示的功能。
So doing this for this case,
所以这样做，
we want to make a very big vector in
我们想要制作一个非常大的载体
a very high-dimensional vector space of all the parameters of
一个非常高维的矢量空间的所有参数
our model and the only parameters that this model
我们的模型和这个模型的唯一参数
has is literally the vector space representations of words.
字面上是字的向量空间表示。
So if there are a 100 dimensional word representations,
所以，如果有一个100维的单词表示，
they're sort of a 100 parameters for aardvark and context,
它们是土豚和环境的100个参数，
100 parameters for the word a- in context et cetera going through,
在上下文等单词a-的100个参数，
100 parameters for the word aardvark [NOISE] as a center word et cetera,
单词aardvark [NOISE]作为中心词等100个参数，
et cetera through that gives us a high big vector of parameters to
等等，为我们提供了一个很大的参数向量
optimize and we're gonna run this optimization and then um, move them down.
优化，我们将运行此优化然后嗯，将它们向下移动。
Um, [NOISE] yeah so that's essentially what you do.
嗯，[NOISE]是的，所以这基本上就是你做的。
Um, I sort of wanted to go through um,
嗯，我有点想通过嗯，
the details of this um,
这个细节，
just so we've kind of gone through things concretely to
所以我们已经具体地经历了一些事情
make sure everyone is on the same page.
确保每个人都在同一页面上。
Um, so I suspect that, you know,
嗯，所以我怀疑，你知道，
if I try and do this concretely,
如果我试着具体地这样做，
um, there are a lot of people um,
嗯，有很多人嗯，
that this will bore and some people that are- will bore very badly,
这会让人厌烦，而且有些人会非常糟糕，
um, so I apologize for you,
嗯，所以我为你道歉，
um, but you know,
嗯，但你知道，
I'm hoping and thinking that there's probably
我希望并且认为可能存在
some people who haven't done as much of this stuff recently
有些人最近没有做过这么多的事
and it might just actually be good to do it concretely
具体地说，实际上可能真的很好
and get everyone up to speed right at the beginning. Yeah?
并让每个人在开始时加快速度。是吗？
[inaudible] how do we calculate [inaudible] specifically?
[听不清]我们如何具体计算[音频不清晰]？
Well, so, we- so the way we calculate the,
那么，我们 - 所以我们计算的方式，
the U and V vectors is we're literally going to start with a random vector for
U和V向量我们实际上将从随机向量开始
each word and then we iteratively going to change those vectors a little bit as we learn.
每个单词然后我们迭代地在我们学习的时候稍微改变那些向量。
And the way we're going to work out how to change them is we're gonna say,
我们要弄清楚如何改变它们的方式是我们要说的，
"I want to do optimization," and that is going to be implemented as okay.
“我想做优化”，这将是可以实现的。
We have the current vectors for each word.
我们有每个单词的当前向量。
Let me do some calculus to work out how I could change the word vectors, um, to mean,
让我做一些微积分来弄清楚如何改变单词vector，嗯，意思是，
that the word vectors would calculate a higher probability for
单词向量将计算更高的概率
the words that actually occur in contexts of this center word.
在这个中心词的背景中实际出现的词。
And we will do that,
我们会这样做，
and we'll do it again and again and again,
我们会一次又一次地这样做，
and then will eventually end up with good word vectors.
然后最终将以良好的单词向量结束。
Thank you for that question,
谢谢你的提问，
cause that's a concept that you're meant to have understood.
因为这是一个你应该理解的概念。
Is that how this works and maybe I didn't
这是如何工作的，也许我没有
explain that high-level recipe well enough, yeah.
高级食谱解释得很好，是的。
Okay, so yeah, so let's just go through it. So, we've seen it, right?
好的，是的，所以让我们来看看吧。所以，我们已经看到了，对吧？
So, we had this formula that we wanted to maximize, you know,
所以，我们有这个公式，我们想要最大化，你知道，
our original function which was the product of T equals one to T,
我们的原始函数是T的乘积等于1到T，
and then the product of the words, uh,
然后是单词的产物，呃，
position minus M less than or equal to J,
位置减去M小于或等于J，
less than or equal to M,
小于或等于M，
J not equal to zero of, um,
J不等于零，嗯，
the probability of W. At prime at T
W的概率。在T处的素数
plus J given WT according to the parameters of our model.
根据我们模型的参数，加上给定WT。
Okay, and then we'd already seen that we were gonna convert that
好的，然后我们已经看到我们要转换它
into the function that we're going to use where we have J of Theta,
进入我们将要使用的功能，我们有The of theta，
where we had the minus one on T. Of the sum of T equals one to T of the sum of minus M,
我们在T上有负一个.T的总和等于负M之和的一到T，
less than or equal to J less than or equal to M,
小于或等于J小于或等于M，
J not equal to zero of the log of the probability of W times T, plus J, W,
J不等于W乘以T的概率的对数的零，再加上J，W，
T. Okay, so we had that and then we'd had
好的，所以我们有了，然后我们就有了
this formula that the probability of the outside word given
这个公式表示外部单词给出的概率
the context word is this formula we just went through of xu ot vc over
上下文单词是我们刚刚通过xu ot vc over的公式
the sum of W equals one to the vocabulary size of xu wt vc.
W的总和等于xu wt vc的词汇量。
Okay, so that's sort of our model.
好的，这就是我们的模型。
We want to min- minimize this.
我们想最小化这个。
So, we wanna minimize this and we want to minimize that by changing these parameters.
因此，我们希望最小化这一点，我们希望通过更改这些参数来最小化这一点。
And these parameters are the contents of these vectors.
并且这些参数是这些向量的内容。
And so, what we want to do now,
那么，我们现在想做什么，
is do calculus and we wanna say let's work out in terms of these parameters which are,
是微积分，我们想说让我们根据这些参数来解决这些问题，
u and v vectors, um,
你和v矢量，嗯，
for the current values of the parameters which we initialized randomly.
对于我们随机初始化的参数的当前值。
Like what's the slope of the space?
就像空间的斜率一样？
Where is downhill?
下坡在哪里？
Because if we can work out downhill is,
因为如果我们可以在下坡工作，
we got just gotta walk downhill and our model gets better.
我们得走下坡路，我们的模型变得更好。
So, we're gonna take derivatives and work out what
所以，我们要采取衍生工具并找出解决方案
direction downhill is and then we wanna walk that way, yeah.
下坡的方向是，然后我们想走那条路，是的。
So, why do we wanna maximize that probable edge and like,
所以，为什么我们想要最大限度地利用这个可能的边缘，
like going through every word,
喜欢听完每一个字，
it's like [inaudible] given the [inaudible]
鉴于[听不清]，它就像[音频不清晰]
So, well, so, so,
所以，好吧，所以，所以，
I'm wanting to achieve this, um,
我想要实现这个，嗯，
what I want to achieve for my distributional notion of meaning is,
我想要实现的分布式意义概念是，
I have a meaningful word, a vector.
我有一个有意义的词，一个向量。
And that vector knows what words occur in the context of,
并且该向量知道在上下文中出现的单词，
um, a word- of itself.
嗯，这个词本身。
And knowing what words occur in its context means,
并且知道在其上下文中出现的单词意味着，
it can accurately give
它可以准确地给出
a high probability estimate to those words that occur in the context,
对上下文中出现的单词的高概率估计，
and it will give low probability estimates
它会给出低概率估计
to words that don't typically occur in the context.
通常不会出现在上下文中的单词。
So, you know, if the word is bank,
所以，你知道，如果这个词是银行，
I'm hoping that words like branch,
我希望像分支这样的话，
and open, and withdrawal,
开放和退出
will be given high probability,
会有很高的概率，
cause they tend to occur with the word bank.
因为它们倾向于与银行一起出现。
And I'm hoping that some other words, um,
而且我希望还有其他一些词，嗯，
like neural network or something have
像神经网络或其他东西
a lower probability because they don't tend to occur with the word bank.
概率较低，因为它们不倾向于出现在单词bank中。
Okay, um, does that make sense?
好的，嗯，这有意义吗？
Yeah.
是啊。
Yeah. And the other thing I was,
是啊。而另一件事我，
I'd forgotten meant to comment was, you know, obviously,
我忘了打算评论，你知道，显然，
we're not gonna be able to do this super well or it's just not gonna be able,
我们不能很好地做到这一点，或者它只是不能够，
that we can say all the words in the context is going to
我们可以说上下文中的所有单词都会发生
be this word with probability 0,97, right?
这个词的概率为0,97，对吗？
Because we're using this one simple probability distribution
因为我们正在使用这个简单的概率分布
to predict all words in our context.
预测我们背景中的所有单词。
So, in particular, we're using it to predict 10 different words generally, right?
所以，特别是，我们一般用它来预测10个不同的词，对吧？
So, at best, we can kind of be giving sort of five percent chance to one of them, right?
所以，充其量，我们可以为其中一个提供5％的机会，对吧？
We can't possibly be,
我们不可能，
so guessing right every time.
所以每次都猜对了。
Um, and well, you know,
嗯，嗯，你知道，
they're gonna be different contexts with different words in them.
他们将在不同的语境中使用不同的词语。
So, you know, it's gonna be a very loose model,
所以，你知道，这将是一个非常宽松的模型，
but nevertheless, we wanna capture the fact that, you know,
但是，我们想要捕捉到这样一个事实，你知道，
withdrawal is much more likely, um,
退出的可能性更大，嗯，
to occur near the word bank than something like football.
发生在银行附近而不是像足球这样的东西。
That's, you know, basically what our goal is.
那就是，你知道，基本上我们的目标是什么。
Okay, um, yes, so we want to maximize this,
好的，嗯，是的，所以我们想要最大化这个，
by minimizing this, which means we then want to do some calculus to work this out.
通过最小化这个，这意味着我们然后想要做一些微积分来解决这个问题。
So, what we're then gonna do is,
所以，我们接下来要做的是，
that we're going to say, well,
我们要说，好吧，
these parameters are our word vectors
这些参数是我们的单词向量
and we're gonna sort of want to move these word vectors,
我们会想要移动这些单词向量，
um, to, um, work things out as to how to, um, walk downhill.
嗯，对，嗯，如何工作，嗯，走下坡路。
So, the case that I'm going to do now is gonna look at the parameters of
那么，我现在要做的就是看看参数
this center word vc and work out how to do things with respect to it.
这个中心词汇vc并找出如何处理它的事情。
Um, now, that's not the only thing that you wanna do,
嗯，现在，这不是你唯一想做的事情，
you also want to work out the slope with respect to the uo vector.
你也想找出关于uo向量的斜率。
Um, but I'm not gonna do that because time in class is going to run out.
嗯，但是我不会这样做，因为课堂上的时间会用完。
So, it'd be really good if you did that one at
所以，如果你做的那个真的很棒
home and then you'd feel much more competent.
回家然后你会感觉更有能力。
Right, so then, um, so what I'm wanting you to do is work out the partial derivative with
是的，那么，嗯，所以我想让你做的是找出偏导数
respect to my vc vector representation of this quantity,
尊重我的vc矢量表示这个数量，
that we were just looking at.
我们只是在看。
Which is, um, the quantity in here,
那是，嗯，这里的数量，
um, where we're taking the log of that quantity.
嗯，我们在那里记录那个数量。
Right, the log of the x of u,
对了，你的x的日志，
o, T, v, c,
o，T，v，c，
over the sum of W equals one to V of the x of u,
在W的总和上等于你的x的一到五，
o, T, v, c. Okay,
o，T，v，c。好的，
so this, um, so now we have a log of the division,
所以这个，嗯，所以现在我们有了一个分区的日志，
so that's easy to rewrite, um,
这样很容易改写，嗯，
that we have a partial derivative of the log of
我们有一个日志的偏导数
the numerator minus and
分子减去和
I can distribute the partial derivative.
我可以分发偏导数。
So, I can have minus the partial derivative,
所以，我可以减去偏导数，
um, of the denominator,
嗯，分母，
um, which is log of this thing.
嗯，这是这个东西的日志。
[NOISE]
[噪声]
Okay. Um, so this is sort of what was the numerator and this is what was the denominator.
好的。嗯，所以这就是分子，这就是分母。
Okay. So, um, the part that was the numerator is really easy.
好的。所以，嗯，作为分子的部分真的很容易。
In fact maybe I can fit it in here.
事实上，也许我可以在这里适应它。
Um, so log on exp are just inverses of each other,
嗯，所以登录exp只是彼此的反转，
so they cancel out.
所以他们取消了。
So, we've got the partial derivative of U_o T V_c.
所以，我们得到了U_o T V_c的偏导数。
Okay, so this point I should, um, just, um,
好的，所以这一点我应该，嗯，只是，嗯，
remind people right that this V_c here's a vector of- um,
提醒人们这个V_c这里是一个矢量，
it's still a vector right because we had a 100 dimensional representation of a word.
它仍然是一个向量，因为我们有一个单词的100维表示。
Um, so this is doing multivariate calculus.
嗯，所以这是做多元微积分。
Um, so you know, if you're,
嗯，你知道，如果你是，
if you at all, um,
如果你有，嗯，
remember any of this stuff,
记住这些东西，
you can say, "Ha this is trivial".
你可以说，“哈，这是微不足道的”。
The answer to that is you are done, um and that's great.
答案就是你完成了，嗯，这很棒。
But you know, if you're, um, feeling, um,
但是你知道，如果你是，嗯，感觉，嗯，
not so good on all of this stuff, um,
所有这些东西都不太好，嗯，
and you wanna sort of, um,
你想要那样的，嗯，
cheat a little on the side and try and work out what it is,
在旁边作弊并尝试弄清楚它是什么，
um, you can sort of say,
嗯，你可以说，
"Well, let me um,,
“好吧，我，嗯，
work out the partial derivative,
算出偏导数，
um with respect to one element of this vector like the first element of this vector".
嗯关于这个向量的一个元素，就像这个向量的第一个元素“。
Well, what I actually got here for this dot product is I have U_o one times V_c one,
那么，我实际上为这个点产品得到的是我有U_o一次V_c one，
plus U_o two times V_c two plus dot, dot,
加U_o两次V_c两加点，点，
dot plus U_o 100 times V_c 100, right,
点加U_o 100倍V_c 100，对，
and I'm finding the partial derivative of this with respect to V_c one,
我找到了关于V_c的偏导数，
and hopefully remember that much calculus from high school
并且希望从高中那里记住那么多的微积分
of none of these terms involve V_c one.
这些术语都不涉及V_c。
So, the only thing that's left is this U_o one,
所以，唯一剩下的就是这个U_o，
and that's what I've got there for this dimension.
这就是我在这个方面所拥有的。
So, this particular parameter.
所以，这个特殊的参数。
But I don't only want to do the first component of the V_c vector,
但我不仅想要做V_c矢量的第一个组件，
I also want to do the second component of the V_c vector et cetera,
我还想做V_c矢量等的第二个组件，
which means I'm going to end up with all of them
这意味着我将最终得到所有这些
turning up in precisely one of these things.
恰好出现在其中一件事中。
Um, and so the end result is I get the vector U_o.
嗯，最终结果是我得到了矢量U_o。
Okay. Um, but you know,
好的。嗯，但是你知道，
if you're sort of getting confused and your brain is falling apart,
如果你有点困惑，你的大脑正在崩溃，
I think it can be sort of kind of useful to re- reduce things to sort of um,
我认为将某些东西重新减少到某种程度是有用的，
single dimensional calculus and actually sort of play out what's actually happening.
单维微积分实际上可以解决实际发生的事情。
Um, anyway, this part was easy.
嗯，无论如何，这部分很容易。
The numerator, we get um, U_o.
分子，我们得到你，U_o。
Um, so things aren't quite so nice when we do the denominator.
嗯，所以当我们分母时，事情并不是那么好。
So we now want to have this, um, B_d,
所以我们现在想要这个，嗯，B_d，
V_c of the log of the sum of W equals
W的总和的对数的V_c等于
one to the P_x of U_o T V_c.
一个到U_o T V_c的P_x。
Okay. So, now at this point,
好的。那么，现在在这一点上，
I'm not quite so pretty.
我不是很漂亮。
We've got this log sum X combination that you see a lot,
我们有这个日志和X组合，你看到很多，
and so at this point you have to remember that there was E, the chain rule.
所以在这一点上你必须记住E，链规则。
Okay. So, what we can say is here's you know,
好的。所以，我们可以说这是你知道的，
our function F and here is the body of the function,
我们的函数F，这里是函数体，
and so what we want to do is um,
所以我们想做的是嗯，
do it in two stages.
分两个阶段完成。
Um, so that at the end of the day,
嗯，所以在一天结束时，
we've got this V_c at the end.
我们最后得到了这个V_c。
So, we have sort of some function here.
所以，我们在这里有一些功能。
There's ultimately a function of V_c,
最终有V_c的功能，
and so we gonna do with a chain rule.
所以我们要做一个连锁规则。
We'll say the chain rule is we first take
我们会说链条规则是我们首先采用的
the derivative of this outside thing putting in this body,
这个外面的东西放在这个身体的衍生物，
and then we remember that the derivative of log is one on X.
然后我们记得日志的衍生物是X上的一个。
So, we have one over the sum of W equals one to V of the exp of U_o T V_c
因此，我们有一个超过W的总和，等于U_o T V_c的exp的一到五
and then we need to multiply that by then taking
然后我们需要乘以那个
the derivative of the inside part which is um,
内部的衍生物是嗯，
what we have here.
我们在这里有什么
Okay. Times the derivative of the inside part with
好的。用内部部分的衍生物来计算
the important reminder that you need to do a change of variables,
重要提示你需要改变变量，
and for the inside part use a different variable that you're summing over.
而对于内部部分使用您正在总结的另一个变量。
Okay. So, now we're trying to find the derivative of a sum of X.
好的。所以，现在我们试图找到X之和的导数。
The first thing that we can do is v-very easy.
我们能做的第一件事就是非常容易。
We can move the derivative inside a sum.
我们可以在一个总和内移动导数。
So, we can rewrite that and have at the sum first of the X equals one to
所以，我们可以重写那个，并且在X的第一个等于1
V of the partial derivatives with respect to V_c of the [inaudible].
相对于[听不见]的V_c的偏导数的V.
Um, so that's a little bit of progress.
嗯，这是一点点进步。
Um and that point we have to sort of do the chain rule again, right.
嗯，那一点，我们必须再做一次链规则吧。
So, here is our function and here's the thing in it again which is some function of V_c.
所以，这是我们的功能，这里的内容再次是V_c的一些功能。
So, we again want to do um, the chain rule.
所以，我们再次想做嗯，链规则。
So, [NOISE] we then have well,
那么，[NOISE]我们就好了，
the derivative of X um, is exp.
X um的衍生物是exp。
So, we gonna have the sum of X equals one to V of exp of U_x T V_c,
所以，我们要求X的总和等于U_x T V_c的exp的V，
and then we're going to multiply that by the partial derivative with
然后我们将乘以偏导数乘以
respect to T V_c of the inside U_x T V_c.
关于内部U_x T V_c的T V_c。
Well, we saw that one before, so,
好吧，我们之前看过那个，所以，
the derivative of that is U- well,
那个衍生物就是U-，
yeah, U_x because we're doing it through a different X, right.
是的，U_x因为我们是通过不同的X来做的，对吧。
This then becomes out as U_x,
然后它变成U_x，
and so we have the sum of the X equals one to
所以我们得到X的总和等于1
V of this exp U X T B C times the U_of X.
这个exp UXTBC的V乘以U_of X.
Okay. So, by doing the chain rule twice, we've got that.
好的。所以，通过做两次链式规则，我们已经做到了。
So, now if we put it together, you know,
所以，现在，如果我们把它放在一起，你知道，
the derivative of V_c with respect of the whole thing,
关于整个事物，V_c的衍生物，
this log of the probability of O given C, right.
这个给出C的概率O的对数，对。
That for the numerator it was just U_o,
对于分子而言，它只是U_o，
and then we're subtracting,
然后我们减去，
we had this term here, um,
我们这里有这个词，嗯，
which is sort of a denominator,
这是一种分母，
and then we have this term here which is the numerator.
然后我们这个术语就是分子。
So, we're subtracting in the numerator,
所以，我们在分子中减去，
we have the sum of X equals one to V of
我们有X等于1到V的总和
the exp of U_x T V_c times U_x,
U_x T的表达式V_c乘以U_x，
and then in the denominator, we have um,
然后在分母中，我们有，嗯，
the sum of W equals one to V of exp of U_w T V_c.
W之和等于U_w T V_c的exp与V之比。
Um, okay, so we kind of get that.
嗯，好的，所以我们得到了。
Um, oh wait. Yeah. Yeah, I've gotten.
嗯，等等。是啊。是的，我已经得到了。
Yeah, that's right. Um, okay.
是啊，没错。嗯，好的。
We kind of get that and then we can sort of just re-arrange this a little.
我们得到了那个，然后我们可以稍微重新安排一下。
So, we can have this sum right out front,
所以，我们可以把这笔款项拿出来，
and we can say that this is sort of a big sum of X equals one to V,
我们可以说这是X等于一到V的一大部分，
and we can sort of take that U_x out the end and say, okay.
我们可以把U_x拿出来然后说，好吧。
Let's call that put over here a U_x,
让我们称之为U_x，
and if we do that,
如果我们这样做，
sort of an interesting thing has happened because look right here,
发生了一件有趣的事情，因为看看这里，
we've rediscovered exactly the same form
我们重新发现了完全相同的形式
that we use as our probability distribution for predicting the probability of words.
我们用它作为概率分布来预测单词的概率。
So, this is now simply the probability of X given C according to our model.
因此，根据我们的模型，这现在只是给定C的X的概率。
Um, so we can rewrite this and say that what we're getting is U_o minus the sum of
嗯，所以我们可以改写这个，并说我们得到的是U_o减去总和
X equals one to V of the probability of X given C times U_x.
X等于给定C乘以U_x的X概率的一到五。
This has a kind of an interesting meaning if you think about it.
如果你想一想，这有一种有趣的意义。
So, this is actually giving us, you know,
所以，这实际上是在给我们，你知道，
our slope in this multi-dimensional space
我们在这个多维空间的斜坡
and how we're getting that slope is we're taking
以及我们如何获得这个斜坡是我们正在采取的
the observed representation of
观察到的代表性
the context word and we're subtracting from that what our model thinks um,
上下文单词，我们从中减去我们的模型所认为的，
the context should look like.
上下文应该是这样的。
What does the model think that the context should look like?
模型认为上下文应该是什么样的？
This part here is formal in expectation.
这部分是正式的期望。
So, what you're doing is you're finding the weighted average
所以，你正在做的是找到加权平均值
of the models of the representations of each word,
每个单词的表示模型，
multiplied by the probability of it in the current model.
乘以当前模型中它的概率。
So, this is sort of the expected context word according to our current model,
所以，这是根据我们当前模型的预期上下文单词，
and so we're taking the difference between
所以我们正在采取区别
the expected context word and the actual context word that showed up,
预期的上下文单词和出现的实际上下文单词，
and that difference then turns out to exactly give
然后，这种差异结果恰好给出了
us the slope as to which direction we should be
我们应该是哪个方向的斜率
walking changing the words
走路改变话语
representation in order to improve our model's ability to predict.
表示以提高我们模型的预测能力。
Okay. Um, so we'll,
好的。嗯，所以我们会，
um, assignment two, um, yeah.
嗯，任务二，嗯，是的。
So, um, it'll be a great exercise for you guys,
所以，嗯，对你们来说这将是一次很棒的运动，
um, to in- um,
嗯，嗯，
to try and do that for the cen-, wait,
尝试为中心做这件事，等等，
um I did the center words trying to look context words as well
嗯我做了中心词试图看上下文词
and show you that you can do the same kind of piece of math and have it work out.
并告诉你，你可以做同样的数学，并让它成功。
Um, if I've just got a few minutes left at the end.
嗯，如果我最后还剩下几分钟的话。
Um, what I just wanted to show you if I can get all of this to work right.
嗯，我只是想告诉你，如果我能让所有这些工作正常的话。
Um, let's go [inaudible] this way.
嗯，让我们以这种方式[听不清]。
Okay, find my.
好的，找到我的。
Okay. Um, so I just wanted to just show you a quick example.
好的。嗯，所以我只是想给你一个简单的例子。
So, for the first assignment,
所以，对于第一次任务，
um, again it's an iPython Notebook.
嗯，这是一个iPython笔记本。
So, if you're all set up you sort of can do Jupyter Notebook.
所以，如果你们都设置好了，你可以选择Jupyter Notebook。
Um, and you have some notebook.
嗯，你有一些笔记本。
Um, here's my little notebook I'm gonna show you,
嗯，这是我要告诉你的小笔记本，
um, and the trick will be to make this big enough that people can see it.
嗯，诀窍是让人们可以看到它。
That readable? [LAUGHTER] Okay, um,
那可读吗？ [大笑]好的，嗯，
so right so, so Numpy is the sort of,
所以就这样，所以Numpy是那种，
um, do math package in Python.
嗯，用Python做数学包。
You'll want to know about that.
你会想知道这件事。
If you don't know about it.
如果你不知道它。
Um, Matplotlib is sort of the,
嗯，Matplotlib有点像，
one of the most basic graphing package
最基本的图形包之一
if you don't know about that you're going to want to know about it.
如果你不知道你会想知道它。
This is sort of an IPython or Jupyter special that
这是一种特殊的IPython或Jupyter
lets you have an interactive matplotlib um, inside.
让你在里面有一个交互式matplotlib嗯。
And if you want to get fancy you can play it- play with your graphic styles.
如果你想获得幻想，你可以玩它 - 玩你的图形样式。
Um, there's that.
嗯，就是这样。
Scikit-learn is kind of a general machine learning package.
Scikit-learn是一种通用的机器学习包。
Um, Gensim isn't a deep learning package.
嗯，Gensim不是一个深入的学习包。
Gensim is kind of a word similarity package which started off um,
Gensim是一个单词相似性包，起初是，
with um, methods like Latent Dirichlet analysis.
与嗯，Latent Dirichlet分析等方法。
If you know about that from modelling words
如果你从建模词汇中知道这一点
similarities that sort of grown as a good package um,
类似的东西，有点成长为一个良好的包，嗯，
for doing um, word vectors as well.
为了做，嗯，单词向量。
So, it's quite often used for word vectors and
因此，它经常用于单词向量和
word similarities that sort of efficient for doing things at large-scale.
与大规模做事有效的词汇相似性。
Um, yeah.
嗯，是的
So, I haven't yet told you about will next time we have
所以，我还没有告诉过你下次我们的意愿
our own homegrown form of word vectors which are the GloVe word vectors.
我们自己开发的单词向量形式，即GloVe单词向量。
I'm using them not because it really matters for what I'm showing but you know,
我使用它们并不是因为它对我所展示的内容非常重要，但你知道，
these vectors are conveniently small.
这些载体很方便。
It turns out that the vectors that Facebook and Google
事实证明，Facebook和谷歌的载体
distribute are extremely large vocabulary and extremely high dimensional.
分布是非常大的词汇量和极高的维度。
So take me just too long to load them in
所以我花了太长时间加载它们
the last five minutes of this class where conveniently uh,
这个班的最后五分钟，方便呃，
in our Stanford vectors we have a 100 dimensional vectors, um,
在斯坦福大学的载体中，我们有100维向量，嗯，
and 50 dimensional vectors which are kinda
和50维矢量有点
good for doing small things on a laptop frankly.
善于在笔记本电脑上做小事坦诚。
Um, so, what I'm doing here is Gensim doesn't natively support
嗯，所以，我在这里做的是Gensim本身不支持
GloVe vectors but they actually provide a utility that
GloVe向量，但它们实际上提供了一个实用程序
converts the GloVe file format to the word2vec file format.
将GloVe文件格式转换为word2vec文件格式。
So I've done that. And then I've loaded a pre-trained model of word vectors.
所以我做到了。然后我加载了一个预训练的单词向量模型。
Um, and, so this is what they call a keyed vector.
嗯，所以这就是他们所谓的键控向量。
And so, the keyed vector is nothing fancy.
所以，键控矢量没什么特别的。
It's just you have words like potato and there's a vector that hangs off each one.
只是你有像马铃薯这样的词，每个人都有一个矢量。
So it's really just sort of a big dictionary with a vector for each thing.
所以它真的只是一个大字典，每个东西都有一个向量。
But, so this model has been a trained model where
但是，这个模型已经成为训练有素的模型
we just use the kind of algorithm we looked at and,
我们只是使用我们看到的那种算法，
you know, trained at billions of times fiddling our word vectors.
你知道，数十亿次训练我们的单词向量。
Um, and once we have one we can then, um,
嗯，一旦我们有了，我们可以，嗯，
ask questions like, we can say,
我们可以说，问问题，
what is the most similar word to some other words?
与其他一些词最相似的词是什么？
So we could take something like, um,
所以我们可以采取类似的东西，嗯，
what are the most similar words to Obama let's say?
与奥巴马最相似的话是什么？
And we get back Barrack, Bush, Clinton,
我们回到巴拉克，布什，克林顿，
McCain, Gore, Hillary Dole, Martin, Henry.
麦凯恩，戈尔，希拉里多尔，马丁，亨利。
That seems actually kind of interesting.
这看起来实际上很有趣。
These factors from a few years ago.
这些因素来自几年前。
So we don't have a post- post-Obama staff.
所以我们没有后奥巴马的工作人员。
I mean if you put in another word, um, you know,
我的意思是，如果你再说一句话，嗯，你知道，
we can put in something like banana and we get coconut,
我们可以加入像香蕉这样的东西，我们得到椰子，
mango, bananas, potato, pineapple.
芒果，香蕉，土豆，菠萝。
We get kind of tropical food.
我们得到一种热带食物。
So, you can actually- you can actually ask uh,
所以，你实际上可以 - 你真的可以问呃，
for being dissimilar to words.
与文字不同。
By itself dissimilar isn't very useful.
本身不相似并不是很有用。
So if I ask most similar and I say um,
所以，如果我问大多数类似的，我说嗯，
negative equals, um, banana,
负等于，嗯，香蕉，
um, I'm not sure what your concept of what's most dissimilar to,
嗯，我不确定你最接近什么的概念，
um, banana is, but you know,
嗯，香蕉是，但是你知道，
actually by itself you don't get anything useful out of this, um,
实际上，你自己没有得到任何有用的东西，嗯，
because, um, you just so get these weird really rare words um,
因为，嗯，你只是这样得到这些奇怪的非常罕见的词，嗯，
which, um, [LAUGHTER] definitely weren't the ones who are thinking of.
哪，嗯，[大笑]绝对不是那些想到的人。
Um, but it turns out you can do something really useful with this negative idea
嗯，但事实证明你可以用这个消极的想法做一些非常有用的事情
which was one of
这是其中之一
the highly celebrated results of word vectors when they first started off.
单词向量在他们刚开始时非常着名的结果。
And that was this idea that there is actually dimensions of meaning in this space.
这就是这个想法，在这个空间中实际上有意义的维度。
And so this was the most celebrated example um, which was look,
所以这是最着名的例子，看起来，
what we could do is we could start with the word king and subtract
我们能做的是我们可以从单词king开始减去
from it the meaning of man and then we could add to it the meaning of woman.
从它的意义，然后我们可以增加女人的意义。
And then we could say which word in our vector space as
然后我们可以说我们的向量空间中的哪个词为
most similar in meaning to that word.
与该词最相似的含义。
And that would be a way of sort of doing analogies.
这将是一种类比的方式。
Would be able to do the, um, analogy,
能够做，嗯，类比，
man is the king as woman is to what?
男人是国王，女人是为了什么？
And so, the way we're gonna do that is to say we want to be similar to king
所以，我们要这样做的方式就是说我们希望与国王相似
and woman because they're both positive ones and far away from man.
和女人，因为他们都是积极的，远离人类。
And so, we could do that manually,
所以，我们可以手动完成
here is said manually,
这是手动说的，
most similar positive woman king, negative man.
最相似的积极女人王，消极的男人。
And we can run this and lo and behold it produces queen.
我们可以运行这个并且看到它产生女王。
To make that a little bit easier I defined this analogy,
为了使这更容易一点，我定义了这个类比，
um, analogy predicates so I can run other ones.
嗯，类比谓词所以我可以运行其他的。
And so I can run another one like analogy Japan Japanese,
所以我可以运行另一个像类比日本日语，
Austria is to Austrian.
奥地利是奥地利人。
Um, and you know,
嗯，你知道，
I think it's fair to say that when people first
我认为，当人们第一时，这是公平的
saw that you could have this simple piece of math and run it,
看到你可以用这个简单的数学运算它，
and learn meanings of words.
并学习单词的意义。
I mean it actually just sort of blew people's minds how effective this was.
我的意思是它实际上只是让人们想到这是多么有效。
You know. Like there- there's is no mirrors and strings here, right?
你懂。就像那里 - 这里没有镜子和弦乐，对吧？
You know it's not that I have a separate-
你知道并不是我有一个单独的 -
a special sort of list in my Python where there's a difficult I'm looking up,
我的Python里有一个特殊的列表，我很难找到，
er, for Austria Austrian,
呃，奥地利奥地利，
uh, and things like that.
呃，等等。
But somehow these vector representations are
但不知何故，这些矢量表示是
such that it is actually encoding these semantic relationships,
这样它实际上编码了这些语义关系，
you know, so you can try different ones,
你知道，所以你可以尝试不同的，
you know, like it's not that only this one works.
你知道，就像它不仅仅是这个有效。
I can put in France, it says French.
我说法语可以放在法国。
I can put in Germany, it says German,
我可以把它放在德国，它说德语，
I can put in Australia not Austria and it says Australian,
我可以在澳大利亚而不是奥地利，它说澳大利亚，
you know that somehow if you want this vector representations of words that
你知道如果你想要这个单词的矢量表示
for sort of these ideas like understanding the relationships between words,
对于这些想法，比如理解单词之间的关系，
you're just doing this vector space manipulation on these 100 dimensional numbers,
你只是在这些100维数字上做这个向量空间操作，
that it actually knows about them.This not only the similarities of word meanings but
它实际上知道它们。这不仅仅是词义的相似之处
actually different semantic relationships
实际上是不同的语义关系
between words like country names and their peoples.
在诸如国名和人民之间的词汇之间。
And yeah that's actually pretty amazing.
是的，这真的很神奇。
It really-you know, it's sort of surprising that running such a dumb algorithm on um,
它真的 - 你知道，在um上运行这样一个愚蠢的算法有点令人惊讶，
vectors of numbers could capture so well the meaning of words.
数字向量可以很好地捕捉到词语的含义。
And so that's sort of became the foundation of a lot of sort
所以这就成了很多种类的基础
of modern distributed neural representations of words.
现代分布式词语神经表征。
Okay I'll stop there.
好的，我会在那里停下来。
Thanks a lot guys and see you on Thursday. [NOISE]
非常感谢，周四见到你。 [噪声]